{
    "questions": [
        {
            "Question": "The Storage-to-Storage instructions",
            "optionA": "  have both their operands in the main store. ",
            "optionB": "  which perform an operation on a register operand and an operand which is located in the main store, generally leaving the result in the register, expect in the case of store operation when it is also  ",
            "optionC": "  which perform indicated operations on two fast registers of the machine and have the result in one of the registers ",
            "optionD": "  all of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe Storage-to-Storage instructions have both their operands in the main store. ",
            "keyString": "282920s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The LRU algorithm",
            "optionA": "  pages out pages that have been used recently ",
            "optionB": "  pages out pages that have not been used recently ",
            "optionC": "  pages out pages that have been least used recently ",
            "optionD": "  pages out the first page in a given area E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn a computer operating system that uses paging for virtual memory management, page replacement algorithms decide which memory pages to page out, sometimes called swap out, or write to disk, when a page of memory needs to be allocated. ",
            "keyString": "283360s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following systems software does the job of merging the records from two files into one?",
            "optionA": "  Security software ",
            "optionB": "  Utility program ",
            "optionC": "  Networking software ",
            "optionD": "  Documentation system E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tUtility program systems software does the job of merging the records from two files into one ",
            "keyString": "283391s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Fork is",
            "optionA": "  the dispatching of a task ",
            "optionB": "  the creation of a new job ",
            "optionC": "  the creation of a new process ",
            "optionD": "  increasing the priority of a task E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn computing, particularly in the context of the Unix operating system and its workalikes, fork is an operation whereby a process creates a copy of itself. It is usually a system call, implemented in the kernel. Fork is the primary method of process creation on Unix-like operating systems. ",
            "keyString": "283518s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Thrashing",
            "optionA": "  is   a   natural   consequence   of virtual memory systems ",
            "optionB": "  can    always    be    avoided    by swapping ",
            "optionC": "  always occurs on large computers ",
            "optionD": "  can be caused by poor paging algorithms E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn computer science, thrashing occurs when a computer's virtual memory resources become saturated, leading to a constant state of paging, to the exclusion of most application-level processing. This causes the performance of the computer to degrade or collapse. Source : wikipedia.org ",
            "keyString": "283636s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "In which addressing mode the contents of a register specified in the instruction are first decremented, and then these contents are used as the effective address of the operands?",
            "optionA": "  index addressing ",
            "optionB": "  indirect addressing ",
            "optionC": "  auto increment ",
            "optionD": "  auto decrement E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAuto decrement mode the contents of a register specified in the instruction are first decremented, and then these contents are used as the effective address of the operands ",
            "keyString": "343297s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What is the name given to the values that are automatically provided by software to reduce keystrokes and improve a computer user's productivity?",
            "optionA": "  Defined values ",
            "optionB": "  Fixed values ",
            "optionC": "  Default values ",
            "optionD": "  Special values E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tDefault values are automatically provided by software to reduce keystrokes and improve a computer user's productivity. ",
            "keyString": "343367s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Page stealing",
            "optionA": "  is a sign of an efficient system ",
            "optionB": "  is taking page frames from other working sets ",
            "optionC": "  should be the tuning goal ",
            "optionD": "  is taking larger disk spaces for pages paged out E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tPage stealing is taking page frames from other working sets ",
            "keyString": "343385s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "In MS-DOS 5.0, which is the number that acts as a code to uniquely identify the software product?",
            "optionA": "  MS ",
            "optionB": "  DOS ",
            "optionC": "  MS DOS ",
            "optionD": "  5 E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn MS-DOS 5.0, 5 is the number that acts as a code to uniquely identify the software product? ",
            "keyString": "343399s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Bug means",
            "optionA": "  A logical error in a program ",
            "optionB": "  A  difficult  syntax  error  in  a program ",
            "optionC": "  Documenting programs using an efficient documentation tool ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA software bug is an error, flaw, failure or fault in a computer program or system that causes it to produce an incorrect or unexpected result, or to behave in unintended ways. ",
            "keyString": "343412s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The main function of the dispatcher (the portion of the process scheduler) is",
            "optionA": "  swapping   a process to the disk ",
            "optionB": "  assigning ready process to the CPU ",
            "optionC": "  suspending some of the processes when the CPU load is high ",
            "optionD": "  bring processes from the disk to the main memory E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe main function of the dispatcher is assigning ready process to the CPU ",
            "keyString": "406226s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The errors that can be pointed out by the compiler are",
            "optionA": "  Syntax errors ",
            "optionB": "  Semantic errors ",
            "optionC": "  Logical errors ",
            "optionD": "  Internal errors E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe errors that can be pointed out by the compiler are 'Syntax errors'. ",
            "keyString": "406351s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "When a computer is first turned on or restarted, a special type of absolute loader is executed, called a",
            "optionA": "  \"Compile and Go\" loader ",
            "optionB": "  Boot loader ",
            "optionC": "  Bootstrap loader ",
            "optionD": "  Relating loader E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA bootstrap loader is a program that resides in the computer's EPROM, ROM, or other non-volatile memory. It is automatically executed by the processor when turning on the computer. ",
            "keyString": "406388s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which, of the following checks, cannot be carried out on the input data to a system?",
            "optionA": "  consistency check ",
            "optionB": "  Syntax check ",
            "optionC": "  Range check ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tSyntax check cannot be carried out on the input data to a system. ",
            "keyString": "406419s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A program that converts a high-level language program to a set of instructions that can run on a computer is called a",
            "optionA": "  Compiler ",
            "optionB": "  Debugger ",
            "optionC": "  Editor ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA compiler is computer software that transforms computer code written in one programming language (the source language) into another programming language (the target language). Compilers are a type of translator that support digital devices, primarily computers. The name compiler is primarily used for programs that translate source code from a high-level programming language to a lower level language. Source : wikipedia.org ",
            "keyString": "406461s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which table is a permanent database that has an entry for each terminal symbol.",
            "optionA": "  Terminal table ",
            "optionB": "  Literal table ",
            "optionC": "  Identifier table ",
            "optionD": "  Reductions E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tTerminal table is a permanent database that has an entry for each terminal symbol. ",
            "keyString": "466769s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The function(s) of the Syntax phase is(are)",
            "optionA": "  to recognize the major constructs of the language and to call the appropriate action routines that will generate the intermediate form or matrix for these constructs. ",
            "optionB": "  to build a literal table and an identifier table ",
            "optionC": "  to build a uniform symbol table ",
            "optionD": "  to parse the source program into the basic elements or tokens of the language. E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe functions of the Syntax phase are to recognize the major constructs of the language and to call the appropriate action routines that will generate the intermediate form or matrix for these constructs. ",
            "keyString": "466797s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Swapping",
            "optionA": "  works best with many small partitions ",
            "optionB": "  allows many programs to use memory simultaneously ",
            "optionC": "  allows each program in turn to use the memory ",
            "optionD": "  does not work with overlaying E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tSwapping is allows each program in turn to use the memory ",
            "keyString": "466810s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A disk scheduling algorithm in an operating system causes the disk arm to move back and forth across the disk surface in order to service all requests in its path. This is a",
            "optionA": "  First come first served ",
            "optionB": "  Shortest Seek Time First (SSTE) ",
            "optionC": "  Scan ",
            "optionD": "  FIFO E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "466821s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A translator is best described as",
            "optionA": "  an application software ",
            "optionB": "  a system software ",
            "optionC": "  a hardware component ",
            "optionD": "  all of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA translator is best described as a system software ",
            "keyString": "466834s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Who is called a supervisor of computer activity?",
            "optionA": "  CPU ",
            "optionB": "  OS ",
            "optionC": "  Control Unit ",
            "optionD": "  Application Program ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tOS is called a supervisor of computer activity. ",
            "keyString": "514411s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Font folder is located on",
            "optionA": "  Program folder ",
            "optionB": "  Ms Word file ",
            "optionC": "  Control Panel folder ",
            "optionD": "  Desktop folder ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tFont folder is located on 'Control Panel folder'. ",
            "keyString": "514440s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "From where do you change mouse setting?",
            "optionA": "  Setting >> mouse ",
            "optionB": "  Hardware setting ",
            "optionC": "  Control panel >> mouse ",
            "optionD": "  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "514452s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Work group means",
            "optionA": "  Computer in network ",
            "optionB": "  Individual user ",
            "optionC": "  Connection ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tWork group means Computer in network ",
            "keyString": "514462s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The core of operating system is:",
            "optionA": "  Unix ",
            "optionB": "  Kernel ",
            "optionC": "  Command.com ",
            "optionD": "  None of these ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe core of the operating system is Kernel. ",
            "keyString": "514471s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following does not support more than one program at a time?",
            "optionA": "  DOS ",
            "optionB": "  Linux ",
            "optionC": "  Windows ",
            "optionD": "  Unix ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tDOS is a family of disk operating systems. DOS primarily consists of MS-DOS and a rebranded. Only one program at a time can use them and DOS itself has no functionality to allow more than one program to execute at a time. ",
            "keyString": "569018s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is not an operating system?",
            "optionA": "  DOS ",
            "optionB": "  Linux ",
            "optionC": "  Windows ",
            "optionD": "  Oracle ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tOracle database (Oracle DB) is a relational database management system (RDBMS) from the Oracle Corporation. ",
            "keyString": "569143s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Linux is a(n) ....... operating system",
            "optionA": "  Open source ",
            "optionB": "  Microsoft ",
            "optionC": "  Windows ",
            "optionD": "  Mac ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tLinux is a family of free and open-source software operating systems built around the Linux kernel. Typically, Linux is packaged in a form known as a Linux distribution for both desktop and server use. ",
            "keyString": "569193s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which operating system can you give smallest file name?",
            "optionA": "  Ps/2 ",
            "optionB": "  Dos ",
            "optionC": "  Windows ",
            "optionD": "  Windows NT ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tDOS (Disk Operating System) is an operating system that runs from a hard disk drive. The term can also refer to a particular family of disk operating systems, most commonly MS-DOS (Microsoft Disk Operating System). ",
            "keyString": "569239s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which one is not operating system?",
            "optionA": "  P11 ",
            "optionB": "  OS/2 ",
            "optionC": "  Windows ",
            "optionD": "  Unix ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "569279s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A system program that sets up an executable program in main memory ready for execution is",
            "optionA": "  assembler ",
            "optionB": "  linker ",
            "optionC": "  loader ",
            "optionD": "  compiler E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA system program that sets up an executable program in main memory ready for execution is loader ",
            "keyString": "629716s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following are loaded into main memory when the computer is booted?",
            "optionA": "  internal command instructions ",
            "optionB": "  external command instructions ",
            "optionC": "  utility programs ",
            "optionD": "  word processing instructions E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tInternal command instructions are loaded into main memory when the computer is booted ",
            "keyString": "629749s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The FIFO algorithm",
            "optionA": "  executes first the job that last entered the queue ",
            "optionB": "  executes first the job that first entered the queue ",
            "optionC": "  execute first the job that has been in the queue the longest ",
            "optionD": "  executes first the job with the least processor needs E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe simplest page-replacement algorithm is a FIFO algorithm. The first-in, first-out (FIFO) page replacement algorithm is a low-overhead algorithm that requires little bookkeeping on the part of the operating system. In simple words, on a page fault, the frame that has been in memory the longest is replaced. ",
            "keyString": "629764s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What is the name given to the organized collection of software that controls the overall operation of a computer?",
            "optionA": "  Working system ",
            "optionB": "  Peripheral system ",
            "optionC": "  Operating system ",
            "optionD": "  Controlling system E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tOperating system is the organized collection of software that controls the overall operation of a computer. ",
            "keyString": "629779s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The principle of locality of reference justifies the use of",
            "optionA": "  reenterable ",
            "optionB": "  non reusable ",
            "optionC": "  virtual memory ",
            "optionD": "  cache memory E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe principle of locality of reference justifies the use of cache memory ",
            "keyString": "629792s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "___ is a compromise mode between Shut Down and Sleep mode because it does not consume power and remembers the current state of your desktop",
            "optionA": "  Shut Down ",
            "optionB": "  Restart ",
            "optionC": "  Sleep ",
            "optionD": "  Hibernate ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThis option was designed for laptops and might not be available for all PCs. (For example, PCs with InstantGo don't have the hibernate option.) Hibernate uses less power than sleep and when you start up the PC again, you\u2019re back to where you left off (though not as fast as sleep). Use hibernation when you know that you won't use your laptop or tablet for an extended period and won't have an opportunity to charge the battery during that time. First check to see if this option is available on your PC and if it is, turn it on. Source : microsoft.com ",
            "keyString": "694132s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "You should choose this mode if you don't know how long you won't use your computer but want to have the same desktop state when you resume",
            "optionA": "  Shut Down ",
            "optionB": "  Restart ",
            "optionC": "  Sleep ",
            "optionD": "  Hibernate ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThis option was designed for laptops and might not be available for all PCs. (For example, PCs with InstantGo don't have the hibernate option.) Hibernate uses less power than sleep and when you start up the PC again, you\u2019re back to where you left off (though not as fast as sleep). Use hibernation when you know that you won't use your laptop or tablet for an extended period and won't have an opportunity to charge the battery during that time. First check to see if this option is available on your PC and if it is, turn it on. Source : microsoft.com ",
            "keyString": "694181s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The category of operating system that you most likely have running on your PDA computer is a ....... Operating system",
            "optionA": "  Real time ",
            "optionB": "  Single user, single task ",
            "optionC": "  Single user, multitask ",
            "optionD": "  Multiuser, multitask ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "694207s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Running multiple programs at the same time is called:",
            "optionA": "  Multitasking ",
            "optionB": "  Foreground tasking ",
            "optionC": "  Single tasking ",
            "optionD": "  Symmetric ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tMultitasking, in an operating system, is allowing a user to perform more than one computer task (such as the operation of an application program) at a time. The operating system is able to keep track of where you are in these tasks and go from one to the other without losing information. ",
            "keyString": "694225s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What is the meaning of \"Hibernate\" in Windows XP/Windows 7?",
            "optionA": "  Restart the Computer in safe mode ",
            "optionB": "  Restart the Computer in hibernate mode ",
            "optionC": "  Shutdown the Computer terminating all the running applications ",
            "optionD": "  Shutdown the Computer without closing the running applications ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe computer saves the current state of the system from the computer's RAM to the hard disk, then shuts down. When the computer is restarted, instead of going through the typical boot sequence, the previously saved state is automatically loaded into the RAM. The open windows and running programs from your previous session appear just as they were when the computer entered Hibernate mode. Basically, Hibernate mode acts like Standby mode, except the computer can be completely turned off. Source : techterms.com ",
            "keyString": "694247s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Data encryption",
            "optionA": "  is mostly used by public networks ",
            "optionB": "  is mostly used by financial networks ",
            "optionC": "  cannot be used by private installations ",
            "optionD": "  is not necessary, since data cannot be intercepted E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tData encryption is mostly used by financial networks Data encryption translates data into another form, or code, so that only people with access to a secret key (formally called a decryption key) or password can read it. Encrypted data is commonly referred to as ciphertext, while unencrypted data is called plaintext. ",
            "keyString": "769291s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What is the name given to the process of initializing a microcomputer with its operating system?",
            "optionA": "  Cold booting ",
            "optionB": "  Booting ",
            "optionC": "  Warm booting ",
            "optionD": "  Boot recording E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "769406s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The function(s) of the Storage Assignment is (are)",
            "optionA": "  to assign storage to all variables referenced in the source program. ",
            "optionB": "  to assign storage to all temporary locations that are necessary for intermediate results. ",
            "optionC": "  to assign storage to literals, and to ensure that the storage is allocate and appropriate locations are initialized. ",
            "optionD": "  all of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "769445s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A Processor",
            "optionA": "  is a device that performs a sequence of operations specified by instructions in memory. ",
            "optionB": "  is the device where information is stored ",
            "optionC": "  is a sequence of instructions ",
            "optionD": "  is typically characterized by interactive processing and time of the CPU E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA Processor is a device that performs a sequence of operations specified by instructions in memory. ",
            "keyString": "769481s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "With MS-DOS which command will divide the surface of the blank floppy disk into sectors and assign a unique address to each one?",
            "optionA": "  FORMAT command ",
            "optionB": "  FAT command ",
            "optionC": "  VER command ",
            "optionD": "  CHKDSK command E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "769512s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "An incremental backup",
            "optionA": "  should be done each month ",
            "optionB": "  uses more tapes ",
            "optionC": "  saves all files ",
            "optionD": "  saves only files that have recently changed E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAn incremental backup saves only files that have recently changed ",
            "keyString": "829234s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The powerful text editor called PC-Write can be used by anybody by paying a small fee. Such programs are called",
            "optionA": "  Software ",
            "optionB": "  Shareware ",
            "optionC": "  Firmware ",
            "optionD": "  Mindware E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe powerful text editor called PC-Write can be used by anybody by paying a small fee. Such programs are called Shareware ",
            "keyString": "829364s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The disadvantages of \"Compile and Go\" loading scheme is (are):",
            "optionA": "  a portion of memory is wasted because the core occupied by the assembler is unavailable to the object program. ",
            "optionB": "  it is necessary to retranslate the user's program deck every time it is run. ",
            "optionC": "  it is very difficult to handle multiple segments, especially if the source programs are in different languages, and to produce orderly modular programs. ",
            "optionD": "  all of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "829397s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The operating system of a computer serves as a software interface between the user and",
            "optionA": "  hardware ",
            "optionB": "  peripheral ",
            "optionC": "  memory ",
            "optionD": "  screen E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe operating system of a computer serves as a software interface between the user and hardware ",
            "keyString": "829424s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following statement is true.",
            "optionA": "  The LRU algorithm pages out pages that have been used recently ",
            "optionB": "  Thrashing is a natural consequence of virtual memory systems. ",
            "optionC": "  Seek analysis is used for analysing control-unit busy problems. ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "829447s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A public key encryption system",
            "optionA": "  allows  anyone  to  decode  the transmission ",
            "optionB": "  allows only the correct sender to decode the data ",
            "optionC": "  allows only the correct receiver to decode the data ",
            "optionD": "  does not encode the data before transmitting it E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA public key encryption system allows only the correct receiver to decode the data. ",
            "keyString": "878087s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Feed back queue",
            "optionA": "  are very easy to implement ",
            "optionB": "  dispatch tasks according to execution characteristics ",
            "optionC": "  are used to favor real-time tasks ",
            "optionD": "  require manual intervention to implement properly E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tFeed back queue dispatch tasks according to execution characteristics. ",
            "keyString": "878119s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "In which addressing mode the operand is given explicitly in the instruction?",
            "optionA": "  absolute mode ",
            "optionB": "  immediate mode ",
            "optionC": "  indirect mode ",
            "optionD": "  index mode E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "878133s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The technique, for sharing the time of a computer among several jobs. Which switches jobs so rapidly such that each job appears to have the computer to itself:",
            "optionA": "  time sharing ",
            "optionB": "  time out ",
            "optionC": "  time domain ",
            "optionD": "  FIFO E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "878146s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Capacity planning",
            "optionA": "  requires detailed system performance information ",
            "optionB": "  is independent of the operating system ",
            "optionC": "  does not depend on the monitoring tools available ",
            "optionD": "  is not needed in small installations E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tCapacity planning is independent of the operating system ",
            "keyString": "878158s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What does FAT stands for?",
            "optionA": "  File attribute type ",
            "optionB": "  File allocation table ",
            "optionC": "  Format All Tabs settings ",
            "optionD": "  File for all type ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tFile Allocation Table (FAT) is a computer file system architecture and a family of industry-standard file systems utilizing it. The FAT file system is a continuing standard which borrows source code from the original, legacy file system and proves to be simple and robust. It offers useful performance even in lightweight implementations, but cannot deliver the same performance, reliability and scalability as some modern file systems. It is, however, supported for compatibility reasons by nearly all currently developed operating systems for personal computers and many mobile devices and embedded systems, and thus is a well-suited format for data exchange between computers and devices of almost any type and age from 1981 up to the present. Source : wikipedia.org ",
            "keyString": "963624s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Fonts install from",
            "optionA": "  Add from control panel ",
            "optionB": "  Font setup file ",
            "optionC": "  Font.exe file ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "963660s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which is not concerned with control panel?",
            "optionA": "  Printer ",
            "optionB": "  Run application ",
            "optionC": "  Font ",
            "optionD": "  Keyboard ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tRun application is not concerned with control panel ",
            "keyString": "963677s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Unicode standard is",
            "optionA": "  Keyboard layout ",
            "optionB": "  Software ",
            "optionC": "  Font ",
            "optionD": "  Character encoding system ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tUnicode is a computing industry standard for the consistent encoding, representation, and handling of text expressed in most of the world's writing systems. The standard is maintained by the Unicode Consortium, and as of June 2018 the most recent version, Unicode 11.0, contains a repertoire of 137,439 characters covering 146 modern and historic scripts, as well as multiple symbol sets and emoji. The character repertoire of the Unicode Standard is synchronized with ISO/IEC 10646, and both are code-for-code identical. Source : wikipedia.org ",
            "keyString": "963691s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A ..... is a windows component that is designed to store other components so these can be organized efficiently?",
            "optionA": "  Document ",
            "optionB": "  Window ",
            "optionC": "  Folder ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA Folder is a windows component that is designed to store other components so these can be organized efficiently. ",
            "keyString": "963705s4m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What is the function of folder?",
            "optionA": "  Save files ",
            "optionB": "  Delete files ",
            "optionC": "  Move files ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA digital folder has the same purpose as a physical folder \u2013 to store documents. Computer folders can also store other types of files, such as applications, archives, scripts, and libraries. Folders can even store other folders, which may contain additional files and folders. Folders are designed for organizing files. ",
            "keyString": "9451s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which button might you find in a windows title bar?",
            "optionA": "  Close button ",
            "optionB": "  Maximize button ",
            "optionC": "  Minimize button ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution: ",
            "keyString": "9547s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Press the ..... button to have the window fill the entire screen",
            "optionA": "  Close ",
            "optionB": "  Maximize ",
            "optionC": "  Minimize ",
            "optionD": "  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tPress the Maximize Button to have the window fill the entire screen ",
            "keyString": "9568s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which windows features can be accessed from the start menu?",
            "optionA": "  Help ",
            "optionB": "  Windows Explorer ",
            "optionC": "  Microsoft Network ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "9588s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "....... are list of commands that appear on the screen",
            "optionA": "  GUIS ",
            "optionB": "  Icons ",
            "optionC": "  Menus ",
            "optionD": "  Windows ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tMenus are list of commands that appear on the screen ",
            "keyString": "9603s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is an example of utility?",
            "optionA": "  Antivirus ",
            "optionB": "  Word ",
            "optionC": "  Operating system ",
            "optionD": "  Data recovery ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "66233s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which is built directly on the hardware?",
            "optionA": "  Computer Environment ",
            "optionB": "  Application Software ",
            "optionC": "  Operating System ",
            "optionD": "  Database System ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "66266s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "...... system is built directly on the hardware",
            "optionA": "  Environment ",
            "optionB": "  System ",
            "optionC": "  Operating ",
            "optionD": "  None ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "66281s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The purpose of run command in start menu is to",
            "optionA": "  Launch internet browser ",
            "optionB": "  Open internet explorer ",
            "optionC": "  Open windows explorer ",
            "optionD": "  Start programs ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "66293s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "You can select My Computer icon and press Alt + Enter to",
            "optionA": "  Delete it from desktop permanently ",
            "optionB": "  Open it in Explorer mode ",
            "optionC": "  Open System Properties dialog box ",
            "optionD": "  Pin it on Start menu ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "66305s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is/are external commands?",
            "optionA": "  Edit ",
            "optionB": "  Label ",
            "optionC": "  Sys ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "118597s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which is not an external command?",
            "optionA": "  Edit ",
            "optionB": "  XCOPY ",
            "optionC": "  Sys ",
            "optionD": "  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "118629s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is not essential to shut down your computer?",
            "optionA": "  Save all opened files ",
            "optionB": "  Close all running applications ",
            "optionC": "  Switch off monitor ",
            "optionD": "  Cut off the power supply ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "118643s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What is Dr. Watson?",
            "optionA": "  IT Expert ",
            "optionB": "  Diagnosis tool ",
            "optionC": "  Surgeon ",
            "optionD": "  None ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tDr. Watson is a diagnostic tool that gathers information about your computer when a problem occurs with a program. The information gathered by Dr. Watson is called a snapshot. The snapshot includes information that: Identifies the program that has a problem. ",
            "keyString": "118656s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "You can move a window to a different position on your screen by dragging it by its",
            "optionA": "  Move handle ",
            "optionB": "  Tail ",
            "optionC": "  Status bar ",
            "optionD": "  Title bar ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "118668s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "If special forms are needed for printing the output, the programmer specifies these forms through?",
            "optionA": "  JCL ",
            "optionB": "  JPL ",
            "optionC": "  Utility programs ",
            "optionD": "  Load modules E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tJob Control Language (JCL) is a name for scripting languages used on IBM mainframe operating systems to instruct the system on how to run a batch job or start a subsystem. More specifically, the purpose of JCL is to say which programs to run, using which files or devices for input or output, and at times to also indicate under what conditions to skip a step.",
            "keyString": "168595s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which policy replace a page if it is not in the favoured subset of a process's pages?",
            "optionA": "  FIFO ",
            "optionB": "  LRU ",
            "optionC": "  LFU ",
            "optionD": "  Working set E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "168628s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following can be accesses by transfer vector approach of linking?",
            "optionA": "  External data segments ",
            "optionB": "  External subroutines ",
            "optionC": "  Data located in other procedures ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "168643s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following terms refers to the degree to which data in a database system are accurate and correct?",
            "optionA": "  data security ",
            "optionB": "  data validity ",
            "optionC": "  data independence ",
            "optionD": "  data integrity E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tData integrity is a fundamental component of information security. In its broadest use, \u201cdata integrity\u201d refers to the accuracy and consistency of data stored in a database, data warehouse, data mart or other construct. ",
            "keyString": "168655s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "In analyzing the compilation of PL/I program, the term \"Syntax analysis\" is associated with",
            "optionA": "  recognition of basic syntactic constructs through reductions ",
            "optionB": "  recognition of basic elements and creation of uniform symbols ",
            "optionC": "  creation of more optional matrix ",
            "optionD": "  use of macro processor to produce more optimal assembly code E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "168667s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following Operating systems is better for implementing a Client-Server network",
            "optionA": "  MS DOS ",
            "optionB": "  Windows 95 ",
            "optionC": "  Windows 98 ",
            "optionD": "  Windows 2000 ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "244072s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "My Computer was introduced from",
            "optionA": "  Windows 3.1 ",
            "optionB": "  Windows 3.11 ",
            "optionC": "  Windows 95 ",
            "optionD": "  Windows 98 ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "244299s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following Windows do not have Start button",
            "optionA": "  Windows Vista ",
            "optionB": "  Windows 7 ",
            "optionC": "  Windows 8 ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "244491s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which is the latest version of MS Windows?",
            "optionA": "  Windows 2007 ",
            "optionB": "  Windows 7 ",
            "optionC": "  Windows 11 ",
            "optionD": "  Windows 10 ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "244687s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which operating system doesn't support networking between computers?",
            "optionA": "  Windows 3.1 ",
            "optionB": "  Windows 95 ",
            "optionC": "  Windows 2000 ",
            "optionD": "  Windows NT ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "244870s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which is not external command?",
            "optionA": "  Doskey ",
            "optionB": "  Verify ",
            "optionC": "  Print ",
            "optionD": "  Find ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "331037s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What is the method of handling deadlocks?",
            "optionA": "  Use a protocol to ensure that the system will never enter a deadlock state ",
            "optionB": "  Allow the system to enter the deadlock state and then recover ",
            "optionC": "  Pretend that deadlocks never occur in the system ",
            "optionD": "  All of the Above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "331257s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "To delete a file without allowing it to store in recycle bin",
            "optionA": "  Press Delete key ",
            "optionB": "  Press Shift + Delete key ",
            "optionC": "  Press Ctrl + Delete key ",
            "optionD": "  Press Alt + Delete key ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "331445s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Operating system is a ......",
            "optionA": "  System software ",
            "optionB": "  Application software ",
            "optionC": "  Presentation software ",
            "optionD": "  Database software ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAn operating system (OS) is system software that manages computer hardware and software resources and provides common services for computer programs. ",
            "keyString": "331627s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "To display a shortcut menu for an object you use",
            "optionA": "  Click the object ",
            "optionB": "  Right click the object ",
            "optionC": "  Point the object and press Ctrl+P ",
            "optionD": "  Touch the object on the screen with your finger ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "331819s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Software that measures, monitors, analyzes, and controls real-world events is called:",
            "optionA": "  system software ",
            "optionB": "  real-time software ",
            "optionC": "  scientific software ",
            "optionD": "  business software E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tSoftware that measures, monitors, analyzes, and controls real-world events is called real-time software ",
            "keyString": "386101s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The details of all external symbols and relocation formation (relocation list or map) is provided to linker by",
            "optionA": "  Macro processor ",
            "optionB": "  Translator ",
            "optionC": "  Loader ",
            "optionD": "  Editor E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe details of all external symbols and relocation formation (relocation list or map) is provided to linker by Translator ",
            "keyString": "386136s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The macro processor must perform",
            "optionA": "  recognize macro definitions and macro calls ",
            "optionB": "  save the macro definitions ",
            "optionC": "  expand macros calls and substitute arguments ",
            "optionD": "  all of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "386150s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A development strategy whereby the executive control modules of a system are coded and tested first, is known as",
            "optionA": "  Bottom-up development ",
            "optionB": "  Top-down development ",
            "optionC": "  Left-Right development ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA development strategy whereby the executive control modules of a system are coded and tested first, is known as Top-down development. ",
            "keyString": "386163s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is helpful in evaluating applications software what will best suit your needs?",
            "optionA": "  recommendations by other users ",
            "optionB": "  computer magazines ",
            "optionC": "  objective software reviews ",
            "optionD": "  all of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "386174s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "How can you optimize performance of your computer?",
            "optionA": "  Delete unused files ",
            "optionB": "  Defrag disk ",
            "optionC": "  Scan for virus ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "433027s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Scandisk",
            "optionA": "  Checks the disk ",
            "optionB": "  Give information about disk ",
            "optionC": "  Run from DOS mode ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "433061s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Recently used application file list appears in the Windows operating system",
            "optionA": "  Setting menu ",
            "optionB": "  Documents menu ",
            "optionC": "  Run dialog box ",
            "optionD": "  Programs menu ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "433075s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "....... are specially designed computer chips that reside inside other devices, such as your car or electric thermostat",
            "optionA": "  Server ",
            "optionB": "  Embedded computer ",
            "optionC": "  Robotic computer ",
            "optionD": "  Mainframes ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "433088s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The title bar always displays on",
            "optionA": "  Top of the open windows ",
            "optionB": "  Left side of the open window ",
            "optionC": "  Right side of the open window ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "433099s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The ....... contains commands associated with the My Computer window",
            "optionA": "  Standard menu ",
            "optionB": "  Start menu ",
            "optionC": "  System menu ",
            "optionD": "  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "472830s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "....... is the layer of a computer system between the hardware and the user program",
            "optionA": "  Operating environment ",
            "optionB": "  Operating system ",
            "optionC": "  System environment ",
            "optionD": "  None of these ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "472863s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which is the layer of a computer system between the hardware and the user program",
            "optionA": "  Operating environment ",
            "optionB": "  Operating system ",
            "optionC": "  System environment ",
            "optionD": "  None ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "472877s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "When you start up the computer the boot up storage at which the BIOS versions manufacturer and data are displayed on the monitor is called",
            "optionA": "  Bootstrap ",
            "optionB": "  Power on self test (POST) ",
            "optionC": "  System configuration ",
            "optionD": "  Kernel loading ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "472890s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The operating system is the most common type of ...... Software",
            "optionA": "  Communication ",
            "optionB": "  Application ",
            "optionC": "  System ",
            "optionD": "  Word processing software ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "472903s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Supervisor state is",
            "optionA": "  never used ",
            "optionB": "  entered by programs when they enter the processor ",
            "optionC": "  required to perform any I/O ",
            "optionD": "  only allowed to the operating system E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe supervisor state is a special mode of operation to which the user has no access. When it is in the supervisor state, the processor and its actions are entirely controled by the Operating System (OS). ",
            "keyString": "514553s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following instruction steps, would be written within the diamond-shaped box, of a flowchart?",
            "optionA": "  S = B - C ",
            "optionB": "  IS A<10 ",
            "optionC": "  PRINT A ",
            "optionD": "  DATA X,4Z E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "514585s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following statements is false?",
            "optionA": "  the technique of storage compaction involves moving all occupied areas of storage to one end or other of main storage ",
            "optionB": "  compaction does not involve relocation of programs ",
            "optionC": "  compaction is also know as garbage collection ",
            "optionD": "  the system must stop everything while it performs the compaction E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "514600s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Interprocess communication",
            "optionA": "  is required for all processes ",
            "optionB": "  is usually done via disk drives ",
            "optionC": "  is never necessary, ",
            "optionD": "  allows processes to synchronize activity E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tInterprocess communication allows processes to synchronize activity ",
            "keyString": "514613s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following functions is(are) performed by the loader",
            "optionA": "  allocate space in memory for the programs and resolve symbolic references between object decks ",
            "optionB": "  adjust all address dependent locations, such as address constants, to correspond to the allocated space. ",
            "optionC": "  physically place the machine instructions and data into memory. ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "514625s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Under multiprogramming, turnaround time for short jobs is usually _____ and that for long jobs is slightly _____.",
            "optionA": "  lengthened; shortened ",
            "optionB": "  shortened; lengthened ",
            "optionC": "  shortened; shortened ",
            "optionD": "  lengthened; lengthened E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tUnder multiprogramming, turnaround time for short jobs is usually shortened and that for long jobs is slightly lengthened. ",
            "keyString": "548984s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The most common systems security method is",
            "optionA": "  passwords ",
            "optionB": "  encryption ",
            "optionC": "  firewall ",
            "optionD": "  all of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe most common systems security method is passwords. Password : A password is a string of characters used for authenticating a user on a computer system. Most passwords are comprised of several characters, which can typically include letters, numbers, and most symbols, but not spaces. ",
            "keyString": "549014s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Two basic types of operating systems are:",
            "optionA": "  sequential and direct ",
            "optionB": "  batch and timesharing ",
            "optionC": "  sequential and realtime ",
            "optionD": "  batch and interactive E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "549028s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Daisy chain is a device for",
            "optionA": "  connecting a number of controllers to a device ",
            "optionB": "  connecting a number of devices to a controller ",
            "optionC": "  interconnecting  a number of devices to a number of controllers ",
            "optionD": "  all of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA daisy chain is an interconnection of computer devices, peripherals, or network nodes in series, one after another. It is the computer equivalent of a series electrical circuit. ",
            "keyString": "549040s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "In analyzing the compilation of PL/I program, the term \"Machine independent optimization\" is associated with",
            "optionA": "  recognition of basic syntactic constructs through reductions ",
            "optionB": "  recognition of basic elements and creation of uniform symbols ",
            "optionC": "  creation of more optional matrix ",
            "optionD": "  use of macro processor to produce more optimal assembly code E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "549052s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Whenever you move a directory from one location to another",
            "optionA": "  All files inside the directory are moved ",
            "optionB": "  All the subdirectory inside that directory are moved ",
            "optionC": "  The directory is moved the source file is not moved ",
            "optionD": "  Both A and B ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAll the files inside the directory and inside subdirectory are moved in that location ",
            "keyString": "583551s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The Basic Input Output System (BIOS) resides in",
            "optionA": "  RAM ",
            "optionB": "  ROM ",
            "optionC": "  The CPU ",
            "optionD": "  Memory Cache ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "583585s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following does not occur during the power-on-self-test (POST)?",
            "optionA": "  The scan disk utility begins to run ",
            "optionB": "  The video card and video memory are tested ",
            "optionC": "  The BIOS identification process occurs ",
            "optionD": "  Memory chip are checked to ensure that they are working properly ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "583600s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The maximum size of a write file is limited to only",
            "optionA": "  Name of the file ",
            "optionB": "  Extension of the file ",
            "optionC": "  The amount of memory in your computer ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "583612s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is drop down list?",
            "optionA": "  List ",
            "optionB": "  Combo box ",
            "optionC": "  Text area ",
            "optionD": "  None ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "583624s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "....... is an intermediate storage for deleted files",
            "optionA": "  My computer ",
            "optionB": "  My documents ",
            "optionC": "  Recycle bin ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn computing, the Trash (also known as the Recycle Bin in Windows and by other names in other operating systems ) is temporary storage for files that have been deleted in a file manager by the user, but not yet permanently erased from the file system. Typically, a recycle bin is presented as a special file directory to the user, allowing the user to browse deleted files, undelete those that were deleted by mistake, or delete them permanently (either one by one, or by the \"Empty Trash\" function). ",
            "keyString": "618812s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "We can start the application from?",
            "optionA": "  Log off ",
            "optionB": "  Network place ",
            "optionC": "  Recycle bin ",
            "optionD": "  Run ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tOn the Microsoft Windows operating system, the Run command is used to directly open an application or document whose path is known. It functions more or less like a single-line command line interface ",
            "keyString": "618844s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is not process states?",
            "optionA": "  New ",
            "optionB": "  Running ",
            "optionC": "  Ready ",
            "optionD": "  Finished ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "618859s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "In DOS, the maximum length of filename is",
            "optionA": "  5 ",
            "optionB": "  8 ",
            "optionC": "  11 ",
            "optionD": "  10 ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe older MS-DOS FAT file system supports a maximum of 8 characters for the base file name and 3 characters for the extension, for a total of 12 characters including the dot separator. This is commonly known as an 8.3 file name. ",
            "keyString": "618871s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The question mark (?) indicates in file searching",
            "optionA": "  A single character ",
            "optionB": "  A group of character ",
            "optionC": "  Questions ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "618884s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following operating system reads and reacts in actual time?",
            "optionA": "  Quick Response System ",
            "optionB": "  Real Time System ",
            "optionC": "  Time Sharing System ",
            "optionD": "  Batch Processing System ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA real-time operating system (RTOS) is an operating system (OS) intended to serve real-time applications that process data as it comes in, typically without buffer delays. Processing time requirements (including any OS delay) are measured in tenths of seconds or shorter increments of time. A real time system is a time bound system which has well defined fixed time constraints. ",
            "keyString": "657794s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "All of the following are TRUE regarding virtual memory EXCEPT",
            "optionA": "  Any amount of RAM can be allocated to virtual memory ",
            "optionB": "  The setting for the amount of hard disk drive space to allocate virtual memory can be manually change ",
            "optionC": "  This temporary storage is called the swap file or page file ",
            "optionD": "  Virtual memory is the physical space o the hard drive ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "657880s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The essential difference between an operating system like Linux and one like Windows is that",
            "optionA": "  Windows can run with an Intel processor, whereas Linux cannot ",
            "optionB": "  Linux is a proprietary whereas Windows is not ",
            "optionC": "  There are multiple versions of Linux, but only one version of Windows ",
            "optionD": "  Any programmer can modify Linux code which is not permitted with Windows ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "657905s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What is dispatch latency?",
            "optionA": "  The time taken by the dispatcher to stop one process and start another ",
            "optionB": "  The time taken by the processor to write a file into disk ",
            "optionC": "  The whole time taken by all processor ",
            "optionD": "  None of Above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "657927s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A page fault occurs when",
            "optionA": "  the Deadlock happens ",
            "optionB": "  the Segmentation starts ",
            "optionC": "  the page is found in the memory ",
            "optionD": "  the page is not found in the memory ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAn interrupt that occurs when a program requests data that is not currently in real memory. The interrupt triggers the operating system to fetch the data from a virtual memory and load it into RAM. An invalid page fault or page fault error occurs when the operating system cannot find the data in virtual memory. ",
            "keyString": "657951s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Non-modifiable procedures are called",
            "optionA": "  serially usable procedures ",
            "optionB": "  concurrent procedures ",
            "optionC": "  reentrant procedures ",
            "optionD": "  topdown procedures E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "771867s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The instruction register",
            "optionA": "  is a hardware memory device which denotes the location of the current instruction being executed. ",
            "optionB": "  is a group of electrical circuits (hardware), that performs the intent of instructions fetched from memory. ",
            "optionC": "  contains the address of the memory location that is to be read from or stored into. ",
            "optionD": "  contains a copy of the designated memory location specified by the MAR after a \"read\" or the new contents of the memory prior to a \"write\". E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe instruction register is a group of electrical circuits (hardware), that performs the intent of instructions fetched from memory. ",
            "keyString": "771900s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following scheduling objectives should be applied to the following: the system should admit jobs to create a mix that will keep most devices busy",
            "optionA": "  to be fair ",
            "optionB": "  to balance resource utilization ",
            "optionC": "  to obey priorities ",
            "optionD": "  to be predictable E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "771914s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Multiprogramming systems:",
            "optionA": "  are easier to develop than single programming system ",
            "optionB": "  execute each job faster ",
            "optionC": "  execute more jobs in the same time period ",
            "optionD": "  are used only on large mainframe computers E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tMultitasking has the same meaning of multiprogramming but in a more general sense, as it refers to having multiple (programs, processes, tasks, threads) running at the same time. This term is used in modern operating systems when multiple tasks share a common processing resource (e.g., CPU and Memory). ",
            "keyString": "771927s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Backups should be done",
            "optionA": "  daily for most installations ",
            "optionB": "  weekly for most installations ",
            "optionC": "  as several image copies, followed by an incremental ",
            "optionD": "  as several incrementals, followed by an image copy E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tBackups should be done as several incrementals, followed by an image copy ",
            "keyString": "771939s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A ....... is a named location on a disk where files are stored",
            "optionA": "  Folder ",
            "optionB": "  Pod ",
            "optionC": "  Version ",
            "optionD": "  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tWhen talking about file systems, a folder (also called directory, or catalog) is a way to organize computer files. A folder is a storage space that many files can be placed into to group them together and organize the computer. A folder can also contain other folders. ",
            "keyString": "851310s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which type of command requires additional files to perform specific operations?",
            "optionA": "  Internal commands ",
            "optionB": "  External commands ",
            "optionC": "  Valuable commands ",
            "optionD": "  Primary commands ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "851343s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is system software?",
            "optionA": "  Operating system ",
            "optionB": "  Compiler ",
            "optionC": "  Utilities ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "851357s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A user-interface that is easy to use is considered to be",
            "optionA": "  User-happy ",
            "optionB": "  User-simple ",
            "optionC": "  User-friendly ",
            "optionD": "  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "851370s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A ..... is a flash memory storage device that plugins into a USB port",
            "optionA": "  USB snap drive ",
            "optionB": "  USB flash drive ",
            "optionC": "  USB memory maker drive ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA USB flash drive is a device used for data storage that includes a flash memory and an integrated Universal Serial Bus (USB) interface. Most USB flash drives are removable and rewritable. Physically, they are small, durable and reliable. ",
            "keyString": "851381s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The term \"operating system\" means",
            "optionA": "  a set of programs which controls computer working ",
            "optionB": "  the  way  a  computer  operator works ",
            "optionC": "  conversion of high level language into machine code ",
            "optionD": "  the  way  a  floppy  disk  drive operates E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe term \"operating system\" means a set of programs which controls computer working. ",
            "keyString": "897492s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following might be used to convert high-level language instructions into machine language?",
            "optionA": "  system software ",
            "optionB": "  applications software ",
            "optionC": "  an operating environment ",
            "optionD": "  an interpreter E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "897526s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Indicate which is a pre-emptive scheduling algorithm",
            "optionA": "  Round-robin ",
            "optionB": "  Shortest-job-next ",
            "optionC": "  Priority-based ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tRound-robin is a pre-emptive scheduling algorithm. ",
            "keyString": "897541s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following, is necessary to work on a computer",
            "optionA": "  Compiler ",
            "optionB": "  Operating system ",
            "optionC": "  Assembly ",
            "optionD": "  Interpreter of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tOperating system is necessary to work on a computer. ",
            "keyString": "897553s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Access time is the highest in the case of",
            "optionA": "  floppy disk ",
            "optionB": "  cache ",
            "optionC": "  swapping devices ",
            "optionD": "  magnetic disk E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAccess time is the highest in the case of magnetic disk ",
            "keyString": "897565s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Assembler language",
            "optionA": "  is usually the primary user interface ",
            "optionB": "  requires fixed-format commands ",
            "optionC": "  is a mnemonic form of machine language ",
            "optionD": "  is quite different from the SCL interpreter E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAssembler language is a mnemonic form of machine language ",
            "keyString": "940209s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The primary job of the operating system of a computer is to",
            "optionA": "  command resources ",
            "optionB": "  manage resources ",
            "optionC": "  provide utilities ",
            "optionD": "  be user friendly E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe primary job of the operating system of a computer is to manage resources ",
            "keyString": "940241s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is a measure to test how good or bad a modular design is",
            "optionA": "  Module strength ",
            "optionB": "  Module coupling ",
            "optionC": "  Static analysis ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "940254s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The Operating system manages",
            "optionA": "  Memory ",
            "optionB": "  Processor ",
            "optionC": "  Disks and I/O devices ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "940267s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The primary purpose of an operating system is to:",
            "optionA": "  make computer easier to use ",
            "optionB": "  keep system programmers employed ",
            "optionC": "  make the most efficient use of the hardware ",
            "optionD": "  allow people to sue the computers E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAn operating system (OS) is system software that manages computer hardware and software resources and provides common services for computer programs. For hardware functions such as input and output and memory allocation, the operating system acts as an intermediary between programs and the computer hardware, although the application code is usually executed directly by the hardware and frequently makes system calls to an OS function or is interrupted by it.",
            "keyString": "940280s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following are(is) Language Processor(s)",
            "optionA": "  assembles ",
            "optionB": "  compilers ",
            "optionC": "  interpreters ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "982101s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "In which addressing mode the effective address of the operand is the contents of a register specified in the instruction and after accessing the operand, the contents of this register is incremented to point to the next item in the list?",
            "optionA": "  index addressing ",
            "optionB": "  indirect addressing ",
            "optionC": "  auto increment ",
            "optionD": "  auto decrement E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "982134s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The memory allocation scheme subject to \"external\" fragmentation is",
            "optionA": "  segmentation ",
            "optionB": "  swapping ",
            "optionC": "  pure demand paging ",
            "optionD": "  multiple contiguous fixed partitions E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe memory allocation scheme subject to \"external\" fragmentation is segmentation. ",
            "keyString": "982149s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "While working with MS-DOS, which command will you use to transfer a specific file from one disk to another?",
            "optionA": "  DISKCOPY ",
            "optionB": "  COPY ",
            "optionC": "  RENAME ",
            "optionD": "  FORMAT E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tWorking with MS-DOS, 'COPY' command will you use to transfer a specific file from one disk to another? ",
            "keyString": "982161s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What is the name of the operating system for the laptop computer called MacLite?",
            "optionA": "  Windows ",
            "optionB": "  DOS ",
            "optionC": "  MS-DOS ",
            "optionD": "  OZ E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tOZ operating system for the laptop computer called MacLite. ",
            "keyString": "982173s5m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Copying a process from memory to disk to allow space for other processes is Called",
            "optionA": "  Swapping ",
            "optionB": "  Deadlock ",
            "optionC": "  Demand Paging ",
            "optionD": "  Page Fault ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tCopying a process from memory to disk to allow space for other processes is called Swapping ",
            "keyString": "76724s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Any files deleted in Windows goes into",
            "optionA": "  Trash can ",
            "optionB": "  Recycle bin ",
            "optionC": "  Deleted Files ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAny files deleted in Windows goes into Recycle bin. ",
            "keyString": "76757s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is a disk compression tool?",
            "optionA": "  Drive space ",
            "optionB": "  Scan disk ",
            "optionC": "  Defragmenter ",
            "optionD": "  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tDrive Space is a disk compression utility supplied with MS-DOS starting from version 6.0. The purpose of Drive Space is to increase the amount of data the user could store on disks, by transparently compressing and decompressing data on-the-fly. It is primarily intended for use with hard drives, but use for floppy disks is also supported. ",
            "keyString": "76771s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What does Belady's Anomaly related to?",
            "optionA": "  Page Replacement Algorithm ",
            "optionB": "  Memory Management Algorithm ",
            "optionC": "  Deadlock Prevention Algorithm ",
            "optionD": "  Disk Scheduling Algorithm ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn computer storage, Belady's Anomaly is the name given to the phenomenon where increasing the number of page frames results in an increase in the number of page faults for a given memory access pattern. This phenomenon is commonly experienced when using the First in First Out (FIFO) page replacement algorithm. ",
            "keyString": "76785s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A ..... allows you to write on screen with a digital pen and convert that writing into characters that the PC can process",
            "optionA": "  Monitor RS ",
            "optionB": "  Tablet PC ",
            "optionC": "  Database manager ",
            "optionD": "  Media Center ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA'Tablet PC' allows you to write on screen with a digital pen and convert that writing into characters that the PC can process. ",
            "keyString": "76796s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "In analyzing the compilation of PL/I program, the description \"creation of more optimal matrix\" is associated with",
            "optionA": "  Assembly and output ",
            "optionB": "  Code generation ",
            "optionC": "  Syntax analysis ",
            "optionD": "  Machine independent optimization E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "118223s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "In memory systems, boundary registers",
            "optionA": "  are used for temporary program variable storage ",
            "optionB": "  are only necessary with fixed partitions ",
            "optionC": "  track page boundaries ",
            "optionD": "  track the beginning and ending of programs E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "118256s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is true for machine language.",
            "optionA": "  Repeated execution of program segments ",
            "optionB": "  Depicting flow of data in a system ",
            "optionC": "  A sequence of instructions which, when followed properly, solves a problem ",
            "optionD": "  the language which communicates with the computer using only the binary digits 1 and 0. E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe language which communicates with the computer using only the binary digits 1 and 0. ",
            "keyString": "118270s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is not applications software?",
            "optionA": "  Word processing ",
            "optionB": "  Spreadsheet ",
            "optionC": "  UNIX ",
            "optionD": "  Desktop publishing E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "118283s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Scissoring enables",
            "optionA": "  a part of data to be displayed ",
            "optionB": "  entire data to be displayed ",
            "optionC": "  full data display on full area of screen ",
            "optionD": "  no data to be displayed E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "118294s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following separates primary file and extension is",
            "optionA": "  Dot ",
            "optionB": "  Period ",
            "optionC": "  Point ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "160292s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "In Microsoft windows, the graphical pattern on the desktop used as background for windows is",
            "optionA": "  Icons ",
            "optionB": "  Wall paper ",
            "optionC": "  Picture ",
            "optionD": "  Background ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tMore commonly referred to as a desktop background in Windows, a wallpaper is an image that is used as a backdrop on any graphical user interface that has a desktop. More plainly, it is the picture or pattern you see on the main screen after your computer has booted up. ",
            "keyString": "160378s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "All of the following are task performed by the operating system except",
            "optionA": "  Managing hardware on the computer ",
            "optionB": "  Controlling the access that application program has to the CPU ",
            "optionC": "  Performing housekeeping task like file compression and disk defragmentation ",
            "optionD": "  Provides an interface for user to interact with computer ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "160407s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is not an operating system?",
            "optionA": "  CP / M ",
            "optionB": "  Unix ",
            "optionC": "  Pascal ",
            "optionD": "  MS DOS ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "160430s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Operating system is like a",
            "optionA": "  Government ",
            "optionB": "  Police ",
            "optionC": "  Parliament ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe operating system provides the basic rules, conventions, protections, and services necessary for the functioning of application programs such as editors, spreadsheets, browsers, and games. Government plays a similar role in the functioning of a modern society. Government furnishes the rules, conventions, protections, and basic services necessary for the smooth functioning and interactions of businesses and individuals. ",
            "keyString": "160450s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The function of Dir/W is",
            "optionA": "  Show all details of file ",
            "optionB": "  Show only file name and directory name ",
            "optionC": "  Shows only directory ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "202504s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Page stealing",
            "optionA": "  Is a sign of an efficient system ",
            "optionB": "  Is taking page frame from other working sets ",
            "optionC": "  Should be the turning goal ",
            "optionD": "  Is taking layer disk space for page in page out ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "202536s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What do you mean by dialog box?",
            "optionA": "  Interactive message box ",
            "optionB": "  Group of options ",
            "optionC": "  Set of controls ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "202550s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Dial up connection allows you to",
            "optionA": "  Connect ISP ",
            "optionB": "  Internet ",
            "optionC": "  Server ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA dial-up connection is established when two or more communication devices use a public switched telephone network (PSTN) to connect to an Internet service provider (ISP). ",
            "keyString": "202562s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "To properly exit Windows",
            "optionA": "  Click the stop button on the desktop ",
            "optionB": "  Click the exit button on the desktop ",
            "optionC": "  Select shut down from Start menu ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "202574s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is not a multitasking operating system?",
            "optionA": "  Windows ",
            "optionB": "  Linux ",
            "optionC": "  Win NT ",
            "optionD": "  DOS ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tDOS (Disk Operating System) is not a multitasking operating system ",
            "keyString": "243120s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "You should choose Sleep option when",
            "optionA": "  The computer is tired after working for the whole day ",
            "optionB": "  You are leaving for a very short time and want to resume you work shortly ",
            "optionC": "  When computer gets hanged frequently. Let it sleep for some time ",
            "optionD": "  You finish working and going to bed ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tSleep mode, sometimes called standby or suspend mode, is a power-sparing state that a computer can enter when not in use. The computer's state is maintained in RAM (random access memory). A computer usually wakes from sleep mode through touching a key, clicking the mouse or pressing the power button. ",
            "keyString": "243203s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The ..... displays the name of every computer user on the computer",
            "optionA": "  Wish list screen ",
            "optionB": "  Command screen ",
            "optionC": "  Welcome screen ",
            "optionD": "  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tWelcome screen displays the name of every computer user on the computer display screen (Computer Monitor). ",
            "keyString": "243224s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The category of software most appropriate for controlling the design and layout of complex document like newsletters and brochure is:",
            "optionA": "  Word processing ",
            "optionB": "  Computer aided design ",
            "optionC": "  Web page authoring ",
            "optionD": "  Desktop publishing ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "243245s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which one is not a system tool?\n",
            "optionA": "  Backup ",
            "optionB": "  Disk defragment ",
            "optionC": "  Virus scanning ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "243262s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What is the initial value of the semaphore to allow only one of the many processes to enter their critical section?",
            "optionA": "  8 ",
            "optionB": "  1 ",
            "optionC": "  16 ",
            "optionD": "  0 E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "285025s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Four necessary conditions for deadlock to exist are: mutual exclusion, no-preemption, circular wait and",
            "optionA": "  hold and wait ",
            "optionB": "  deadlock avoidance ",
            "optionC": "  race around condition ",
            "optionD": "  buffer overflow E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "285056s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "If you do not know which version of MS-DOS you are working with, which command will you use after having booted your operating system?",
            "optionA": "  FORMAT command ",
            "optionB": "  DIR command ",
            "optionC": "  VER command ",
            "optionD": "  DISK command E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn computing, ver is a command in various DOS, FlexOS, OS/2 and Microsoft Windows command line interpreters such as COMMAND.COM, cmd.exe and 4DOS/4NT. It prints the name and version of the operating system or the command shell. ",
            "keyString": "285070s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A partitioned data set is most used for",
            "optionA": "  a program or source library ",
            "optionB": "  storing program data ",
            "optionC": "  storing backup information ",
            "optionD": "  storing ISAM files E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA partitioned data set is most used for a program or source library ",
            "keyString": "285082s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Page-map table is",
            "optionA": "  A data file ",
            "optionB": "  A directory ",
            "optionC": "  Used for address translation ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tPage-map table is used for address translation ",
            "keyString": "285093s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A hardware device that is capable of executing a sequence of instructions, is known as",
            "optionA": "  CPU ",
            "optionB": "  ALU ",
            "optionC": "  CU ",
            "optionD": "  Processor E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA hardware device that is capable of executing a sequence of instructions, is known as processor ",
            "keyString": "320791s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of following is/are the advantage(s) of modular programming?",
            "optionA": "  The program is much easier to change ",
            "optionB": "  Modules can be reused in other programs ",
            "optionC": "  Easy debugging ",
            "optionD": "  Easy to compile E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "320825s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The function(s) performed by the paging software is (are)",
            "optionA": "  Implementation of the access environment for all programs in the system ",
            "optionB": "  Management of the physical address space ",
            "optionC": "  Sharing and protection ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "320839s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A compiler for a high-level language that runs on one machine and produces code for a different machine is called",
            "optionA": "  optimizing compiler ",
            "optionB": "  one pass compiler ",
            "optionC": "  cross compiler ",
            "optionD": "  multipass compiler E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA compiler for a high-level language that runs on one machine and produces code for a different machine is called cross compiler. ",
            "keyString": "320851s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A critical region is",
            "optionA": "  a program segment that has not been proved bug-free ",
            "optionB": "  a program segment that often causes unexpected system crashes ",
            "optionC": "  a program segment where shared resources are accessed ",
            "optionD": "  one which is enclosed by a pair of P and V operations on semaphores E.  none is the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA critical region is one which is enclosed by a pair of P and V operations on semaphores ",
            "keyString": "320864s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is used to display the content of a certain drive or folder?",
            "optionA": "  Click the drive or folder while holding down the Alt key ",
            "optionB": "  Triple click the drive or folder ",
            "optionC": "  Right click the drive or folder ",
            "optionD": "  Double click the drive or folder ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "359615s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following file menu option saves document to disk?",
            "optionA": "  Save ",
            "optionB": "  Create ",
            "optionC": "  Rename ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "359648s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Booting means",
            "optionA": "  Restarting computer ",
            "optionB": "  Installing program ",
            "optionC": "  Removing errors ",
            "optionD": "  Switch off ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tTo boot a computer is to load an operating system into the computer's main memory or random access memory (RAM). Once the operating system is loaded, it's ready for users to run applications. ",
            "keyString": "359663s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "When you rename a file five times then the number of file in the disk is",
            "optionA": "  1 ",
            "optionB": "  2 ",
            "optionC": "  3 ",
            "optionD": "  5 ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "359675s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "When you open my computer on desktop you see the information of",
            "optionA": "  Hard disk ",
            "optionB": "  CD ",
            "optionC": "  Removable disk ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "359688s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What problem is solved by Dijkstra's banker's algorithm?",
            "optionA": "  mutual exclusion ",
            "optionB": "  deadlock recovery ",
            "optionC": "  deadlock avoidance ",
            "optionD": "  cache coherence E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tDeadlock avoidance problem is solved by Dijkstra's banker's algorithm ",
            "keyString": "405855s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The dispatcher",
            "optionA": "  actually schedules the tasks into the processor ",
            "optionB": "  puts tasks in I/O wait ",
            "optionC": "  is always small and simple ",
            "optionD": "  never changes task priorities E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe dispatcher actually schedules the tasks into the processor. ",
            "keyString": "406097s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "System programs such as Compilers are designed so that they are",
            "optionA": "  reenterable ",
            "optionB": "  non reusable ",
            "optionC": "  serially usable ",
            "optionD": "  recursive E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tSystem programs such as Compilers are designed so that they are reenterable ",
            "keyString": "406228s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "IBM released its first PC in 1981. Can you name the operating system which was most popular at that time?",
            "optionA": "  MS-DOS ",
            "optionB": "  PC-DOS ",
            "optionC": "  OS/360 ",
            "optionD": "  CP/M E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tCP/M, originally standing for Control Program/Monitor and later Control Program for Microcomputers, is a mass-market operating system created for Intel 8080/85-based microcomputers by Gary Kildall of Digital Research, Inc. Initially confined to single-tasking on 8-bit processors and no more than 64 kilobytes of memory, later versions of CP/M added multi-user variations and were migrated to 16-bit processors. CP/M was displaced by DOS soon after the 1981 introduction of the IBM PC. ",
            "keyString": "406341s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "If the number of bits in a virtual address of a program is 16 and the page size is 0.5 K bytes, the number of pages in the virtual address space is",
            "optionA": "  16 ",
            "optionB": "  32 ",
            "optionC": "  64 ",
            "optionD": "  128 E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIf the number of bits in a virtual address of a program is 16 and the page size is 0.5 K bytes, the number of pages in the virtual address space is 128. ",
            "keyString": "406453s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The system/370 assembler language",
            "optionA": "  allows the programmer to write base registers and displacements explicitly in the source program. ",
            "optionB": "  is used to remember which of the general-purpose registers are currently available as base registers, and what base addresses they contain. ",
            "optionC": "  allows multiple programs to reside in separate areas of core at the same time. ",
            "optionD": "  is a term that refers to the control programs of an operating system. E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe system/370 assembler language allows the programmer to write base registers and displacements explicitly in the source program. ",
            "keyString": "453830s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Scheduling is",
            "optionA": "  allowing jobs to use the processor ",
            "optionB": "  unrelated to performance consideration ",
            "optionC": "  not required in uniprocessor systems ",
            "optionD": "  the same regard-less of the purpose of the system E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe process scheduling is the activity of the process manager that handles the removal of the running process from the CPU and the selection of another process on the basis of a particular strategy. Process scheduling is an essential part of Multiprogramming operating systems. ",
            "keyString": "454050s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What scheduling algorithm allows processes that are logical runnable to be temporarily suspended?",
            "optionA": "  preemptive scheduling ",
            "optionB": "  non-preemptive scheduling ",
            "optionC": "  FIFO ",
            "optionD": "  FCFS E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:Preemptive Scheduling: A scheduling discipline is preemptive if, once a process has been given the CPU can taken away. The strategy of allowing processes that are logically runable to be temporarily suspended is called Preemptive Scheduling and it is contrast to the \"run to completion\" method. ",
            "keyString": "454239s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "In an absolute loading scheme, which loader function is accomplished by the loader",
            "optionA": "  Reallocation ",
            "optionB": "  Allocation ",
            "optionC": "  Linking ",
            "optionD": "  Loading E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn an absolute loading scheme, Loading function is accomplished by the loader ",
            "keyString": "454424s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The computational technique used to compute the disk storage address of individual records is called:",
            "optionA": "  bubble memory ",
            "optionB": "  key fielding ",
            "optionC": "  dynamic reallocation ",
            "optionD": "  hashing E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe computational technique used to compute the disk storage address of individual records is called hashing. ",
            "keyString": "454602s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What is the name of the operating system which was originally designed by scientists and engineers for use by scientists and engineers?",
            "optionA": "  XENIX ",
            "optionB": "  UNIX ",
            "optionC": "  OS/2 ",
            "optionD": "  MS DOS E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "504304s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The most common security failure is",
            "optionA": "  carelessness by users ",
            "optionB": "  depending on passwords ",
            "optionC": "  too much emphasis on preventing physical access ",
            "optionD": "  insufficient technology used to prevent breaches E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "504570s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Terminal Table",
            "optionA": "  contains all constants in the program ",
            "optionB": "  a permanent table of decision rules in the form of patterns for matching with the uniform symbol table to discover syntactic structure. ",
            "optionC": "  consists of a full or partial list of the token's as they appear in the program. Created by Lexical analysis and used for syntax analysis and interpretation ",
            "optionD": "  a permanent table which lists all key words and special symbols of the language in symbolic form. E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "504722s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Block or buffer caches are used",
            "optionA": "  to improve disk performance ",
            "optionB": "  to handle interrupts ",
            "optionC": "  to increase the capacity of main memory ",
            "optionD": "  to speed up main memory read operation E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tBlock or buffer caches are used to improve disk performance. ",
            "keyString": "504849s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The practice of \"bundling\" refers to",
            "optionA": "  selling computers alone ",
            "optionB": "  selling peripheral devices with computer ",
            "optionC": "  selling software to run on computers ",
            "optionD": "  giving  away  software  with  a computer purchase E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "505451s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is not a video file extension?",
            "optionA": "  .avi ",
            "optionB": "  .wav ",
            "optionC": "  .mpeg ",
            "optionD": "  .mov ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\t.wav is not a video file extension ",
            "keyString": "571184s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What is the extension of the font file?",
            "optionA": "  .ttf ",
            "optionB": "  .mdb ",
            "optionC": "  .fft ",
            "optionD": "  .txt ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\t.ttf is the extension of the font file ",
            "keyString": "571216s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which is not executable file?",
            "optionA": "  .com ",
            "optionB": "  .exe ",
            "optionC": "  .bat ",
            "optionD": "  .txt ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\t.txt is not executable file ",
            "keyString": "571230s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "To move to the beginning of a line of text, press the __________ key.",
            "optionA": "  A ",
            "optionB": "  PgUp ",
            "optionC": "  Enter ",
            "optionD": "  Home ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tTo move to the beginning of a line of text, press the Home key. ",
            "keyString": "571243s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "When was MS Windows operating system introduced?",
            "optionA": "  1975 ",
            "optionB": "  1985 ",
            "optionC": "  1995 ",
            "optionD": "  2000 ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tMicrosoft Windows is a group of several graphical operating system families, all of which are developed, marketed, and sold by Microsoft. Microsoft introduced an operating environment named Windows on November 20, 1985, as a graphical operating system shell for MS-DOS in response to the growing interest in graphical user interfaces (GUIs). Source : wikipedia.org ",
            "keyString": "571255s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Underlined text, such as text and folder names is referred to as",
            "optionA": "  Hyperlink ",
            "optionB": "  Menu ",
            "optionC": "  Source drive ",
            "optionD": "  None of these ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "624234s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is suitable after you install new drivers?",
            "optionA": "  Shut Down ",
            "optionB": "  Restart ",
            "optionC": "  Sleep ",
            "optionD": "  Hibernate ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "624274s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Windows displays various options to shutdown. Which is suitable at the end of day?",
            "optionA": "  Shut Down ",
            "optionB": "  Restart ",
            "optionC": "  Sleep ",
            "optionD": "  Hibernate ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "624289s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following shutdown method is often called Warm Boot?",
            "optionA": "  Shut Down ",
            "optionB": "  Restart ",
            "optionC": "  Sleep ",
            "optionD": "  Hibernate ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "624302s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "______ is most often done after fixing a problem, adding a new program or making configuration change",
            "optionA": "  Shut Down ",
            "optionB": "  Restart ",
            "optionC": "  Sleep ",
            "optionD": "  Hibernate ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "624315s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Multiprogramming",
            "optionA": "  is a method of memory allocation by which the program is subdivided into equal portions, or pages and core is subdivided into equal portions or blocks. ",
            "optionB": "  consists of those addresses that may be generated by a processor during execution of a computation. ",
            "optionC": "  is a method of allocating processor time. ",
            "optionD": "  allows multiple programs to reside in separate areas of core at the time. E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tMultiprogramming allows multiple programs to reside in separate areas of core at the time. ",
            "keyString": "671360s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A translator which reads an entire programme written in a high level language and converts it into machine language code is:",
            "optionA": "  assembler ",
            "optionB": "  translator ",
            "optionC": "  compiler ",
            "optionD": "  system software E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "671395s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The advantage(s) inherent to using high level languages is (are)",
            "optionA": "  Fewer people, less management and shorter transition in learning time ",
            "optionB": "  Improved debugging capability, and superior documentation ",
            "optionC": "  A greater degree of machine independence ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "671409s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Addressing modes",
            "optionA": "  defines the fundamental method of determining effective operand addresses ",
            "optionB": "  are variations in the use of fundamental addressing structures, or some associated actions which are related to addressing. ",
            "optionC": "  performs indicated operations on two fast registers of the machine and leave the result in one of the registers. ",
            "optionD": "  all of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAddressing modes are variations in the use of fundamental addressing structures, or some associated actions which are related to addressing. ",
            "keyString": "671422s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "In which way(s) a macro processor for assembly language can be implemented:",
            "optionA": "  independent two-pass processor ",
            "optionB": "  independent one-pass processor ",
            "optionC": "  processor incorporated into pass 1 of a standard two-pass assembler ",
            "optionD": "  all of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "671434s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is an example of a real time operating system?",
            "optionA": "  Lynx ",
            "optionB": "  MS DOS ",
            "optionC": "  Windows XP ",
            "optionD": "  Process Control ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA real-time operating system (RTOS) is an operating system (OS) intended to serve real-time applications that process data as it comes in, typically without buffer delays. Processing time requirements (including any OS delay) are measured in tenths of seconds or shorter increments of time. ",
            "keyString": "719632s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following operating system does not implement the multitasking truly?",
            "optionA": "  Windows 98 ",
            "optionB": "  Windows NT ",
            "optionC": "  Windows XP ",
            "optionD": "  MS DOS ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tMultitasking, in an operating system, is allowing a user to perform more than one computer task (such as the operation of an application program) at a time. The operating system is able to keep track of where you are in these tasks and go from one to the other without losing information. MS DOS does not implement the multitasking. ",
            "keyString": "719665s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following windows version support 64 bit processor?",
            "optionA": "  Windows 98 ",
            "optionB": "  Windows 2000 ",
            "optionC": "  Windows XP ",
            "optionD": "  Windows 95 ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tMicrosoft Windows XP Professional x64 Edition, released on April 25, 2005, is an edition of Windows XP for x86-64 personal computers. It is designed to use the expanded 64-bit memory address space provided by the x86-64 architecture. The primary benefit of moving to 64-bit is the increase in the maximum allocatable random-access memory (RAM). ",
            "keyString": "719680s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What program runs first after computer is booted and loading GUI?",
            "optionA": "  Desktop Manager ",
            "optionB": "  File Manager ",
            "optionC": "  Windows Explorer ",
            "optionD": "  Authentication ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "719693s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following operating system do you choose to implement a client server network?",
            "optionA": "  MS DOS ",
            "optionB": "  Windows ",
            "optionC": "  Windows 98 ",
            "optionD": "  Windows 2000 ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "719705s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The SJF algorithm executes first the job",
            "optionA": "  that last entered the queue ",
            "optionB": "  that first entered the queue ",
            "optionC": "  that has been in the queue the longest ",
            "optionD": "  with the least processor needs E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:The shortest job first (SJF) or shortest job next, is a scheduling policy that selects the waiting process with the smallest execution time to execute next.",
            "keyString": "760708s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "In which of the storage placement strategies a program is placed in the largest available hole in the main memory?",
            "optionA": "  best fit ",
            "optionB": "  first fit ",
            "optionC": "  worst fit ",
            "optionD": "  buddy E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "760776s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is a block device",
            "optionA": "  mouse ",
            "optionB": "  printer ",
            "optionC": "  terminals ",
            "optionD": "  disk E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA block device is a computer data storage device that supports reading and (optionally) writing data in fixed-size blocks, sectors, or clusters. These blocks are generally 512 bytes or a multiple thereof in size. ",
            "keyString": "760791s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The problem of thrashing is affected significantly by:",
            "optionA": "  program structure ",
            "optionB": "  program size ",
            "optionC": "  primary-storage size ",
            "optionD": "  all of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe problem of thrashing is affected significantly by program structure ",
            "keyString": "760814s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following software types is used to simplify using systems software?",
            "optionA": "  spreadsheet ",
            "optionB": "  operating environment ",
            "optionC": "  timesharing ",
            "optionD": "  multitasking E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn computing, time-sharing is the sharing of a computing resource among many users by means of multiprogramming and multi-tasking at the same time. Its introduction in the 1960s and emergence as the prominent model of computing in the 1970s represented a major technological shift in the history of computing. ",
            "keyString": "760828s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is a type of systems software used on microcomputers?",
            "optionA": "  MS-DOS ",
            "optionB": "  PC-DOS ",
            "optionC": "  Unix ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "802527s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The working set theory of programming behaviour of processes running within an operating system involves",
            "optionA": "  the collection of pages that a process accesses ",
            "optionB": "  disk scheduling mechanisms ",
            "optionC": "  coalescing holes in memory ",
            "optionD": "  assigning the CPU to processes E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe working set theory of programming behaviour of processes running within an operating system involves the collection of pages that a process accesses ",
            "keyString": "802561s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Operating system is",
            "optionA": "  A collection of hardware components ",
            "optionB": "  A collection of input-output devices ",
            "optionC": "  A collection of software routines ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tOperating system is a collection of software routines ",
            "keyString": "802575s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A file organization component of a VSAM file is:",
            "optionA": "  relative record data set ",
            "optionB": "  keyed sequential data set ",
            "optionC": "  entry sequential data set ",
            "optionD": "  all of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "802588s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What is the name given to the software which can be legally compiled and often used for free?",
            "optionA": "  Shareware program ",
            "optionB": "  Public domain program ",
            "optionC": "  Firmware program ",
            "optionD": "  Mindware E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tPublic-domain software (program) refers to any program that is not copyrighted. Public-domain software (program) is free and can be used without restrictions. The term public-domain software is often used incorrectly to include freeware, free software that is nevertheless copyrighted. ",
            "keyString": "802600s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "In an absolute loading scheme, which loader function is accomplished by assembler.",
            "optionA": "  Reallocation ",
            "optionB": "  Allocation ",
            "optionC": "  Linking ",
            "optionD": "  Loading E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "844023s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The command interpreter",
            "optionA": "  is usually the primary user interface ",
            "optionB": "  requires fixed format commands ",
            "optionC": "  is menu drive ",
            "optionD": "  is quite different from the SCL interpreter E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe command interpreter is usually the primary user interface ",
            "keyString": "844058s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A task in a blocked state",
            "optionA": "  is executable ",
            "optionB": "  is running ",
            "optionC": "  must still be placed in the run queues ",
            "optionD": "  is waiting for same temporarily unavailable resources E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA task in a blocked state is waiting for same temporarily unavailable resources ",
            "keyString": "844072s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "System maintenance:",
            "optionA": "  is usually not necessary ",
            "optionB": "  is necessary on all systems, regardless of how good ",
            "optionC": "  is not required if the system is well written ",
            "optionD": "  always requires several programs E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tSystem maintenance is necessary on all systems, regardless of how good ",
            "keyString": "844085s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following statements is not true about the FORTRAN language?",
            "optionA": "  FORTRAN is a high level language ",
            "optionB": "  A FORTRAN program, written for the IBM-PC, is totally different from a FORTRAN program written for execution on the SUN machine ",
            "optionC": "  FORTRAN is extensively used to write programs for performing scientific computations ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "844097s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The process of transferring data intended for a peripheral device into a disk (or intermediate store) so that it can be transferred to peripheral at a more convenient time or in bulk, is known as",
            "optionA": "  multiprogramming ",
            "optionB": "  spooling ",
            "optionC": "  caching ",
            "optionD": "  virtual programming E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe process of transferring data intended for a peripheral device into a disk (or intermediate store) so that it can be transferred to peripheral at a more convenient time or in bulk, is known as 'spooling'. ",
            "keyString": "880894s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Block caches or buffer caches are used",
            "optionA": "  to improve disk performance ",
            "optionB": "  to handle interrupts ",
            "optionC": "  to increase the capacity of the main memory ",
            "optionD": "  to speed up main memory read operation E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tBlock caches or buffer caches are used to improve disk performance ",
            "keyString": "880927s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following statements is false?",
            "optionA": "  a small page size causes large page tables ",
            "optionB": "  internal fragmentation is increased with small pages ",
            "optionC": "  a large page size causes instructions and data that will not be referenced brought into primary storage ",
            "optionD": "  I/O transfers are more efficient with large pages E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "880941s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The action of parsing the source program into the proper syntactic classes is known as",
            "optionA": "  syntax analysis ",
            "optionB": "  lexical analysis ",
            "optionC": "  interpretation analysis ",
            "optionD": "  general syntax analysis E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe action of parsing the source program into the proper syntactic classes is known as lexical analysis ",
            "keyString": "880953s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which, of the following is not true about the description of a decision table?",
            "optionA": "  A decision table is easy to modify ",
            "optionB": "  A decision table is directly understood by the computer ",
            "optionC": "  A decision table is easy to understand ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA decision table is directly understood by the computer is not true about the description of a decision table ",
            "keyString": "880965s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is characteristic of an operating system?",
            "optionA": "  resource management ",
            "optionB": "  error recovery ",
            "optionC": "  memory management ",
            "optionD": "  All the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "972502s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "In MS-DOS, relocatable object files and load modules have extensions",
            "optionA": "  .OBJ and .COM or .EXE, respectively ",
            "optionB": "  .COM and .OBJ, respectively ",
            "optionC": "  .EXE and .OBJ, respectively ",
            "optionD": "  .DAS and .EXE, respectively E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn MS-DOS, relocatable object files and load modules have extensions is .OBJ and .COM or .EXE, respectively. .OBJ : OBJ is a geometry definition file format first developed by Wavefront Technologies for its Advanced Visualizer animation package. The file format is open and has been adopted by other 3D graphics application vendors. .COM : The domain name com is a top-level domain in the Domain Name System of the Internet. Its name is derived from the word commercial, indicating its original intended purpose for domains registered by commercial organizations. Later, the domain opened for general purposes. .EXE : EXE is a file extension for an executable file format. An executable is a file that contains a program - that is, a particular kind of file that is capable of being executed or run as a program in the computer. An executable file can be run by a program in Microsoft DOS or Windows through a command or a double click.",
            "keyString": "972546s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The state transition initiated by the user process itself in an operating system is",
            "optionA": "  block ",
            "optionB": "  dispatch ",
            "optionC": "  wake up ",
            "optionD": "  timer run out E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe state transition initiated by the user process itself in an operating system is block. ",
            "keyString": "972561s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following program is not a utility?",
            "optionA": "  Debugger ",
            "optionB": "  Editor ",
            "optionC": "  Spooler ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "972573s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The function(s) of file system is (are):",
            "optionA": "  to provide complete file naming freedom to the users and to permit controlled sharing of files ",
            "optionB": "  to provide for long and short term storage of files with appropriate economic tradeoffs. ",
            "optionC": "  to provide security against loss of information due to system failure ",
            "optionD": "  all of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "972585s6m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Poor response time are usually caused by",
            "optionA": "  Process busy ",
            "optionB": "  High I/I rates ",
            "optionC": "  High paging rate ",
            "optionD": "  Any of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "9738s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Where will store data first time when you copy",
            "optionA": "  Clipboard ",
            "optionB": "  Clipbook ",
            "optionC": "  Hard disk ",
            "optionD": "  CD ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn clipboard first time data is store when copy. ",
            "keyString": "9771s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "GUI means",
            "optionA": "   Graphic user interface ",
            "optionB": "  Geographic user interface ",
            "optionC": "  Graphical user interface ",
            "optionD": "  Geometric user interface ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe graphical user interface (GUI), is a type of user interface that allows users to interact with electronic devices through graphical icons and visual indicators such as secondary notation, instead of text-based user interfaces, typed command labels or text navigation. ",
            "keyString": "9785s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Use of icons and windows are characteristics of ....... interface",
            "optionA": "  Command driven ",
            "optionB": "  Windows orientated ",
            "optionC": "  Graphical user ",
            "optionD": "  Menu driven ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tUse of icons and windows are characteristics of graphical user interface. ",
            "keyString": "9797s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Windows can run",
            "optionA": "  One application only ",
            "optionB": "  Two applications only ",
            "optionC": "  Four applications only ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "9809s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A relocate program form is one which",
            "optionA": "  cannot be made to execute in any area of storage other than the one designated for it at the time of its coding or translation. ",
            "optionB": "  consists of a program and relevant information for its relocation. ",
            "optionC": "  can itself performs the relocation of its address-sensitive portions. ",
            "optionD": "  all of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA relocate program form is one which consists of a program and relevant information for its relocation. ",
            "keyString": "49794s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "If you want to execute more than one program at a time, the systems software you are using must be capable of:",
            "optionA": "  word processing ",
            "optionB": "  virtual memory ",
            "optionC": "  compiling ",
            "optionD": "  multitasking E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIf you want to execute more than one program at a time, the systems software you are using must be capable of multitasking. ",
            "keyString": "49827s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "In analyzing the compilation of PL/I program, the description \"resolving symbolic address (labels) and generating machine language\" is associated with",
            "optionA": "  Assembly and output ",
            "optionB": "  Code generation ",
            "optionC": "  Storage assignment ",
            "optionD": "  Syntax analysis E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "49841s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Round-robin scheduling",
            "optionA": "  allows interactive tasks quicker access to the processor ",
            "optionB": "  is quite complex to implement ",
            "optionC": "  gives each task the same chance at the processor ",
            "optionD": "  allows processor-bound tasks more time in the processor E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tRound-robin scheduling gives each task the same chance at the processor ",
            "keyString": "49855s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What is the name of the system which deals with the running of the actual computer and not with the programming problems?",
            "optionA": "  Operating system ",
            "optionB": "  Systems program ",
            "optionC": "  Object program ",
            "optionD": "  Source program E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tSystems program deals with the running of the actual computer and not with the programming problems. ",
            "keyString": "49867s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following key is used to move the pointer from one pane to next pane?",
            "optionA": "  F3 ",
            "optionB": "  F4 ",
            "optionC": "  F5 ",
            "optionD": "  F6 ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tF6 key is used to move the pointer from one pane to next pane ",
            "keyString": "87838s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "In a folder, which of the following key is used to rename the file or folder",
            "optionA": "  F3 ",
            "optionB": "  F4 ",
            "optionC": "  F2 ",
            "optionD": "  F7 ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn a folder, \"F2\" key is used to rename the file or folder ",
            "keyString": "87872s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A character that represents one or more unknown character is",
            "optionA": "  Wildcard character ",
            "optionB": "  All file name ",
            "optionC": "  Extensions ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "87886s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following file format supports in Windows 7?",
            "optionA": "  NTFS ",
            "optionB": "  BSD ",
            "optionC": "  EXT ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tNTFS file format supports in Windows 7 ",
            "keyString": "87899s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Anything you cut or copy on to the clipboard remains there until you",
            "optionA": "  Change it ",
            "optionB": "  Clear ",
            "optionC": "  Exit windows ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "87911s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The ....... is a temporary storage area in memory where you can attach text or graphics information",
            "optionA": "  Clipboard ",
            "optionB": "  Copyboard ",
            "optionC": "  Both a and b ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe Clipboard is a temporary storage area in memory where you can attach text or graphics information. ",
            "keyString": "169914s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "An embedded object might appear in a document as",
            "optionA": "  Embedding ",
            "optionB": "  Linking ",
            "optionC": "  Both ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "170480s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "When a computer is first turned on or restarted, a special type of absolute loader called",
            "optionA": "  Compile and go loader ",
            "optionB": "  Boot loader ",
            "optionC": "  Bootstrap loader ",
            "optionD": "  Relating loader ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tWhen a computer is first turned on or restarted, a special type of absolute loader called 'Bootstrap loader'. ",
            "keyString": "171028s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "In which type of the following OS, the response time is very crucial.",
            "optionA": "  Network Operating System ",
            "optionB": "  Real Time Operating System ",
            "optionC": "  Batch Operating System ",
            "optionD": "  Unix Operating System ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tReal Time Operating System, the response time is very crucial. ",
            "keyString": "171624s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is a correct association between a vendor and an operating system",
            "optionA": "  Redhat Linux ",
            "optionB": "  Microsoft Unix ",
            "optionC": "  AT & T DOS ",
            "optionD": "  Novell Linux ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tRedhat Linux is a correct association between a vendor and an operating system. ",
            "keyString": "172252s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The CPU, after receiving an interrupt from an I/O device",
            "optionA": "  halts for a predetermined time ",
            "optionB": "  hands over control of address bus and data bus to the interrupting device ",
            "optionC": "  branches off to the interrupt service routine immediately ",
            "optionD": "  branches off to the interrupt service routine after completion of the current instruction E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "230664s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Seeks analysis",
            "optionA": "  is used for analyzing paging problems ",
            "optionB": "  is used for analyzing device busy problems ",
            "optionC": "  is used for analyzing control-unit busy problems ",
            "optionD": "  is only shown on real-time displays E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tSeeks analysis is used for analyzing device busy problems ",
            "keyString": "230775s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which is a permanent database in the general model of the compiler?",
            "optionA": "  Literal Table ",
            "optionB": "  Identifier Table ",
            "optionC": "  Terminal Table ",
            "optionD": "  Source code E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tTerminal Table is a permanent database in the general model of the compiler ",
            "keyString": "231316s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What is the name of the technique in which the operating system of a computer executes several programs concurrently by switching back and forth between them?",
            "optionA": "  Partitioning ",
            "optionB": "  Multitasking ",
            "optionC": "  Windowing ",
            "optionD": "  Paging E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn Multitasking the operating system of a computer executes several programs concurrently by switching back and forth between them. ",
            "keyString": "231356s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Operating system",
            "optionA": "  links a program with the subroutines it references ",
            "optionB": "  provides a layered, user-friendly interface ",
            "optionC": "  enables the programmer to draw a flowchart ",
            "optionD": "  all of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tOperating system provides a layered, user-friendly interface ",
            "keyString": "231382s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Once text has been cut to the clipboard, you can ...... that text into another document\n",
            "optionA": "  Paste ",
            "optionB": "  Copy ",
            "optionC": "  Transfer ",
            "optionD": "  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "304767s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What is the function of radio button?",
            "optionA": "  To select multiple option ",
            "optionB": "  To select single option ",
            "optionC": "  To select all option ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA radio button or option button is a graphical control element that allows the user to choose only one of a predefined set of mutually exclusive options. ",
            "keyString": "304981s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The Banker's algorithm is used",
            "optionA": "  to rectify deadlock ",
            "optionB": "  to detect deadlock ",
            "optionC": "  to prevent deadlock ",
            "optionD": "  to solve deadlock ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe Banker algorithm, sometimes referred to as the detection algorithm, is a resource allocation and deadlock avoidance algorithm developed by Edsger Dijkstra that tests for safety by simulating the allocation of predetermined maximum possible amounts of all resources, and then makes an \"s-state\" check to test for possible deadlock conditions for all other pending activities, before deciding whether allocation should be allowed to continue. Source : wikipedia.org ",
            "keyString": "305166s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The primary purpose of an operating system is:",
            "optionA": "  To make the most efficient use of the computer hardware ",
            "optionB": "  To allow people to use the computer ",
            "optionC": "  To keep systems programmers employed ",
            "optionD": "  To make computers easier to use ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAn operating system (OS) is system software that manages computer hardware and software resources and provides common services for computer programs. For hardware functions such as input and output and memory allocation, the operating system acts as an intermediary between programs and the computer hardware, although the application code is usually executed directly by the hardware and frequently makes system calls to an OS function or is interrupted by it. Source : wikipedia.org ",
            "keyString": "305344s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "You can use print manage window",
            "optionA": "  To check status of files in the print queue ",
            "optionB": "  To cancel the print job ",
            "optionC": "  To interrupt printing ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "305520s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The memory which allocates space for DOS and application is called\n",
            "optionA": "  Expanded memory ",
            "optionB": "  Cache memory ",
            "optionC": "  Virtual memory ",
            "optionD": "  Conventional memory ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn DOS memory management, conventional memory, also called base memory, is the first 640 kilobytes (640 \u00d7 1024 bytes) of the memory on IBM PC or compatible systems. It is the read-write memory directly addressable by the processor for use by the operating system and application programs. ",
            "keyString": "350377s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The operating system creates _____ from the physical computer",
            "optionA": "  Virtual space ",
            "optionB": "  Virtual computers ",
            "optionC": "  Virtual device ",
            "optionD": "  None ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn computing, a virtual machine is an emulation of a computer system. Virtual machines are based on computer architectures and provide the functionality of a physical computer. ",
            "keyString": "350413s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which menu bar selection would you access to open file?",
            "optionA": "  Option ",
            "optionB": "  Help ",
            "optionC": "  View ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "350428s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which mode loads minimal set of drivers when starting Windows?",
            "optionA": "  Safe Mode ",
            "optionB": "  Normal Mode ",
            "optionC": "  VGA Mode ",
            "optionD": "  Network Support Mode ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tSafe mode is a diagnostic mode of a computer operating system (OS). It can also refer to a mode of operation by application software. In Windows, safe mode only allows essential system programs and services to start up at boot. Safe mode is intended to help fix most, if not all problems within an operating system. It is also widely used for removing rogue security software. ",
            "keyString": "350441s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following are loaded in safe mode?",
            "optionA": "  Keyboard driver ",
            "optionB": "  Mouse driver ",
            "optionC": "  VGA drive ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "350453s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is a program group?",
            "optionA": "  Word pad ",
            "optionB": "  Paint brush ",
            "optionC": "  Accessories ",
            "optionD": "  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAccessories is a program group ",
            "keyString": "401191s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A program in execution is called",
            "optionA": "  A Paging ",
            "optionB": "  A Process ",
            "optionC": "  A virtual memory ",
            "optionD": "  A Demand Page ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA program in execution is called 'A Process' ",
            "keyString": "401817s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What is the default file extension created by notepad?",
            "optionA": "  .doc ",
            "optionB": "  .html ",
            "optionC": "  .txt ",
            "optionD": "  .tif ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\t.txt is the default file extension created by notepad. ",
            "keyString": "402500s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is not the user file extension?",
            "optionA": "  .ppt ",
            "optionB": "  .xls ",
            "optionC": "  .sys ",
            "optionD": "  .doc ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\t.sys is not the user file extension ",
            "keyString": "404556s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is the extension of WordPad?",
            "optionA": "  .ppt ",
            "optionB": "  .xls ",
            "optionC": "  .rtf ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\t.rtf is the extension of WordPad ",
            "keyString": "405633s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "If you hard disk is partitioned into 3 drives, the number of recycle bin for that hard disk is",
            "optionA": "  1 ",
            "optionB": "  2 ",
            "optionC": "  3 ",
            "optionD": "  4 ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "458950s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The date and time displays on",
            "optionA": "  Taskbar ",
            "optionB": "  Status bar ",
            "optionC": "  System tray ",
            "optionD": "  Launch pad ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "459166s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "...... runs on a computer hardware and serves as a platform for other system to run on",
            "optionA": "  Operating system ",
            "optionB": "  Application system ",
            "optionC": "  System software ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "459365s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which runs on computer hardware and serve as platform for other software to run on?",
            "optionA": "  Operating System ",
            "optionB": "  Application Software ",
            "optionC": "  System Software ",
            "optionD": "  All ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "459776s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which is the first program run on a computer when the computer boots up?",
            "optionA": "  System software ",
            "optionB": "  Operating system ",
            "optionC": "  System operations ",
            "optionD": "  None ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "459991s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "In a magnetic disk, data is recorded in a set of concentric tracks which are subdivided into",
            "optionA": "  periods ",
            "optionB": "  sectors ",
            "optionC": "  zones ",
            "optionD": "  groups E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn a magnetic disk, data is recorded in a set of concentric tracks which are subdivided into sectors ",
            "keyString": "530261s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The total time to prepare a disk drive mechanism for a block of data to be read from it is",
            "optionA": "  latency ",
            "optionB": "  latency plus transmission time ",
            "optionC": "  latency plus seek time ",
            "optionD": "  latency   plus   seek   time   plus transmission time E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe total time to prepare a disk drive mechanism for a block of data to be read from it is latency plus seek time ",
            "keyString": "530505s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Part of a program where the shared memory is accessed and which should be executed invisibly is called",
            "optionA": "  semaphores ",
            "optionB": "  directory ",
            "optionC": "  critical section ",
            "optionD": "  mutual exclusion E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tPart of a program where the shared memory is accessed and which should be executed invisibly is called critical section ",
            "keyString": "530702s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Indicate which, of the following, is not true about Nassi-Shneiderman charts",
            "optionA": "  These charts are type of graphical design tool ",
            "optionB": "  These charts cannot represent CASE constructs ",
            "optionC": "  These charts can represent three fundamental control structures ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "530894s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What is the name of the operating system that reads and reacts in terms of actual time.",
            "optionA": "  Batch system ",
            "optionB": "  Quick response system ",
            "optionC": "  Real time system ",
            "optionD": "  Time sharing system E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "531086s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What do you mean by Memory Compaction?",
            "optionA": "  Combine multiple equal memory holes into one big hole ",
            "optionB": "  Combine multiple small memory holes into one big hole ",
            "optionC": "  Divide big memory hole into small holes ",
            "optionD": "  Divide memory hole by 2 ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "601443s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Desktop is a",
            "optionA": "  Provides work space ",
            "optionB": "  Screen saver ",
            "optionC": "  Display program ",
            "optionD": "  Working with my document ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "601641s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is not a system tool?",
            "optionA": "  Scandisk ",
            "optionB": "  Drive space ",
            "optionC": "  Disk defragmenter ",
            "optionD": "  Doskey ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "601818s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following statement about directories is false?",
            "optionA": "  Directories can exist inside directories ",
            "optionB": "  The root directory is always at the highest level ",
            "optionC": "  Directories cannot be renamed ",
            "optionD": "  Directories can be deleted ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "601988s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The program that is responsible for loading the operating system into RAM is called",
            "optionA": "  BIOS ",
            "optionB": "  Bootstrap program ",
            "optionC": "  Device driver ",
            "optionD": "  Supervisor program ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA bootstrap is the program that initializes the operating system (OS) during startup. The term bootstrap or bootstrapping originated in the early 1950s. It referred to a bootstrap load button that was used to initiate a hardwired bootstrap program, or smaller program that executed a larger program such as the OS. ",
            "keyString": "602179s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is default mode for Windows to start?",
            "optionA": "  Command Prompt ",
            "optionB": "  Safe Mode ",
            "optionC": "  Normal Mode ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "682133s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The file system \"NTFS\" stands for",
            "optionA": "  New Type File System ",
            "optionB": "  Never Terminated File System ",
            "optionC": "  New Technology File System ",
            "optionD": "  Non Terminated File System ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tNTFS (New Technology File System) is a proprietary file system developed by Microsoft. Starting with Windows NT 3.1, it is the default file system of the Windows NT family. ",
            "keyString": "682430s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which one of the following is not the function of Operating System?",
            "optionA": "  Resource Management ",
            "optionB": "  File Management ",
            "optionC": "  Networking ",
            "optionD": "  Processor Management ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "682636s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "How do you connect internet in your system?",
            "optionA": "  My computer >> dialup networking ",
            "optionB": "  Control panel >> modem ",
            "optionC": "  Network neighborhood ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "682932s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The following applications may appear on system tray except",
            "optionA": "  System Clock ",
            "optionB": "  Volume Control ",
            "optionC": "  Network Connection ",
            "optionD": "  MS Office Suite ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tMS Office Suite is not appear in system tray ",
            "keyString": "683491s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "For how many processes which are sharing common data, the Dekker's algorithm implements mutual exclusion?",
            "optionA": "  1 ",
            "optionB": "  2 ",
            "optionC": "  3 ",
            "optionD": "  4 E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tDekker's algorithm is the first known correct solution to the mutual exclusion problem in concurrent programming. The solution is attributed to Dutch mathematician Th. J. Dekker by Edsger W. Dijkstra in an unpublished paper on sequential process descriptions and his manuscript on cooperating sequential processes. ",
            "keyString": "767833s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The file structure that redefines its first record at a base of zero uses the term:",
            "optionA": "  relative organization ",
            "optionB": "  key fielding ",
            "optionC": "  dynamic reallocation ",
            "optionD": "  hashing E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "768033s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What is the name given to all the programs inside the computer with makes it usable?",
            "optionA": "  Application software ",
            "optionB": "  System software ",
            "optionC": "  Firm ware ",
            "optionD": "  Shareware E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "768206s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Semaphores",
            "optionA": "  synchronize critical resources to prevent deadlock ",
            "optionB": "  synchronize critical resources to prevent contention ",
            "optionC": "  are used to do I/O ",
            "optionD": "  are used for memory management E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tSemaphores synchronize critical resources to prevent deadlock ",
            "keyString": "768377s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The advantage(s) of incorporating the macro processor into pass 1 is(are):",
            "optionA": "  many functions do not have to be implemented twice. ",
            "optionB": "  Functions are combined and it is not necessary to create intermediate files as output from the macros processor and input to the assembler. ",
            "optionC": "  more flexibility is available to the programmer in that he may use all the features of the assembler in conjunction with macros. ",
            "optionD": "  all of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "768562s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The box on ....... that allows you to choose where to go and is located below the standard toolbar",
            "optionA": "  System menu ",
            "optionB": "  Address bar ",
            "optionC": "  Menu bar ",
            "optionD": "  None of these ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe box on Address bar that allows you to choose where to go and is located below the standard toolbar ",
            "keyString": "875262s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A ...... is a set of computer instructions that carry out a task on the computer",
            "optionA": "  Program ",
            "optionB": "  Database ",
            "optionC": "  Memory files ",
            "optionD": "  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA Program is a set of computer instructions that carry out a task on the computer ",
            "keyString": "875471s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A real time operating system is most likely to be used for which of the following task?",
            "optionA": "  Controlling access to a shared printer in a network ",
            "optionB": "  Ensuring that system clock works correctly on server ",
            "optionC": "  Managing the access to system files in a laptop computers ",
            "optionD": "  Controlling the fuel injection system of an automobile engines ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "875660s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "An operating system is a program or a group of programs that",
            "optionA": "  Helps in checking the spelling of Word ",
            "optionB": "  Maintain the relationship in Database ",
            "optionC": "  Manages the resources of the Computer ",
            "optionD": "  Performs the calculations of cells in Excel ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "875844s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What is the function of an operating system?",
            "optionA": "  Manages computer\u2019s resources very efficiently ",
            "optionB": "  Takes care of scheduling jobs for execution ",
            "optionC": "  Manages the flow of data and instructions ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "876023s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Special software to create a job queue is called a",
            "optionA": "  Drive ",
            "optionB": "  Spooler ",
            "optionC": "  Interpreter ",
            "optionD": "  Linkage editor E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tSpecial software to create a job queue is called a spooler ",
            "keyString": "940236s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "All the time a computer is switched on, its operating system software has to stay in",
            "optionA": "  main storage ",
            "optionB": "  primary storage ",
            "optionC": "  floppy disk ",
            "optionD": "  disk drive E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAll the time a computer is switched on, its operating system software has to stay in primary storage ",
            "keyString": "940472s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Can you name of the major Operating System used in computers?",
            "optionA": "  MS DOS ",
            "optionB": "  OS/2 ",
            "optionC": "  UNIX ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "940691s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is not an advantage of multiprogramming?",
            "optionA": "  increased throughput ",
            "optionB": "  shorter response time ",
            "optionC": "  decreased operating-system overhead ",
            "optionD": "  ability to assign priorities to jobs E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "940893s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Virtual Memory",
            "optionA": "  is a method of memory allocation by which the program is subdivided into equal portions, or pages and core is subdivided into equal portions or blocks. ",
            "optionB": "  consists of those addresses that may be generated by a processor during execution of a computation. ",
            "optionC": "  is a method of allocating processor time. ",
            "optionD": "  allows multiple programs to reside in separate areas of core at the time. E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tVirtual Memory consists of those addresses that may be generated by a processor during execution of a computation. ",
            "keyString": "941090s7m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The ....... is the drive containing the files to be copied",
            "optionA": "  Source drive ",
            "optionB": "  Destination drive ",
            "optionC": "  USB drive ",
            "optionD": "  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "2731s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which one of the following is not a multitasking operating system?",
            "optionA": "  DOS ",
            "optionB": "  Windows ",
            "optionC": "  Unix ",
            "optionD": "  Linux ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tDOS is not a multitasking operating system. DOS did however provide a Terminate and Stay Resident (TSR) function which allowed programs to remain resident in memory. ",
            "keyString": "3429s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The most recent version of MAC OS is based on the ...... operating system",
            "optionA": "  Windows ",
            "optionB": "  Linux ",
            "optionC": "  Unix ",
            "optionD": "  CMOS ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "3684s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "In Windows, start button is used to",
            "optionA": "  Run applications ",
            "optionB": "  Device setting ",
            "optionC": "  Turn off the system ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe Start button was first introduced with the release of Microsoft Windows 95 and has been featured in all releases of Windows since. The Start button allows users to access their run applications, device setting, turn off the system, computer programs or configure Microsoft Windows easily by accessing the Start Menu. ",
            "keyString": "3906s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which one is true for unconditional disk formatting?",
            "optionA": "  Destroys every byte of data on a disk by overwriting it with with blank spaces ",
            "optionB": "  Do not check/scan surface after format ",
            "optionC": "  Transfer system files after format ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "4119s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What should be the extension to execute files?",
            "optionA": "  EXE ",
            "optionB": "  BAT ",
            "optionC": "  COM ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tEXE is a file extension for an executable file format. An executable is a file that contains a program - that is, a particular kind of file that is capable of being executed or run as a program in the computer. ",
            "keyString": "77818s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Part of the POST process is to ensure that the test of essential peripheral device coincides with the hardware configuration that stored in",
            "optionA": "  ROM ",
            "optionB": "  The hard drive ",
            "optionC": "  CMOS ",
            "optionD": "  Cache Memory ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tCMOS (complementary metal-oxide-semiconductor) is the term usually used to describe the small amount of memory on a computer motherboard that stores the BIOS settings. ",
            "keyString": "78110s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The memory resident portion of operating system is called the",
            "optionA": "  Registry ",
            "optionB": "  API ",
            "optionC": "  CMOS ",
            "optionD": "  Kernel ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe memory resident portion of operating system is called the Kernel. ",
            "keyString": "79211s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Boot startup process",
            "optionA": "  Loads system files to RAM ",
            "optionB": "  Checks the computer connections ",
            "optionC": "  Clean up the computer memory ",
            "optionD": "  Prepare the computer ready ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tBoot startup process is Loads system files to RAM. ",
            "keyString": "79664s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "When you delete file, where it resides?",
            "optionA": "  Briefcase ",
            "optionB": "  Recycle bin ",
            "optionC": "  CD ",
            "optionD": "  Desktop ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn computing, the Trash is temporary storage for files that have been deleted in a file manager by the user, but not yet permanently erased from the file system. ",
            "keyString": "79872s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is not a characteristic of a daisy chaining priority control scheme?",
            "optionA": "  priority is programmable ",
            "optionB": "  it is relatively easy to add more devices to the chain ",
            "optionC": "  the failure of one device may affect other devices on the chain ",
            "optionD": "  the number of control lines is independent of the number of devices on the chain E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "156673s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Assembler is",
            "optionA": "  a program that places programs into memory and prepares them for execution. ",
            "optionB": "  a program that automate the translation of assembly language into machine language. ",
            "optionC": "  a program that accepts a program written in a high level language and produces an object program. ",
            "optionD": "  is a program that appears to execute a source program as if it were machine language. E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "157201s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Indicate which, of the following, in not true about an interpreter",
            "optionA": "  Interpreter generates an object program from the source program ",
            "optionB": "  Interpreter is a kind of translator ",
            "optionC": "  Interpreter analyses each source statement every time it is to be executed ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "157663s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Object modules generated by assemblers that contain unresolved external references are resolved for two or more object modules by a/an",
            "optionA": "  operating system ",
            "optionB": "  loader ",
            "optionC": "  linker ",
            "optionD": "  compiler E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "158151s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The advantage of a command processor running only built-in commands is:",
            "optionA": "  flexibility to the users in running lists of commands by simply collecting them in named batch command files ",
            "optionB": "  the command set being common across different hardware configurations ",
            "optionC": "  users can create system programs and run them as commands ",
            "optionD": "  the processing is much faster than would other-wise be the case when user defined commands are used E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe advantage of a command processor running only built-in commands is the command set being common across different hardware configurations. ",
            "keyString": "158610s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "When we double click on my computer",
            "optionA": "  Show the content of your saved files ",
            "optionB": "  Show the list of your computer drive ",
            "optionC": "  List of deleted files and folders ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tWhen we double click on my computer show the list of your computer drive. ",
            "keyString": "306506s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is the part of the operating system?",
            "optionA": "  Cell ",
            "optionB": "  FAT ",
            "optionC": "  Kernel ",
            "optionD": "  Disk ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA kernel is the central part of an operating system. It manages the operations of the computer and the hardware - most notably memory and CPU time. There are two types of kernels: A microkernel, which only contains basic functionality; A monolithic kernel, which contains many device drivers. ",
            "keyString": "306966s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Directory is similar to ......",
            "optionA": "  File ",
            "optionB": "  Folder ",
            "optionC": "  Item ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn computing, a directory is a file system cataloging structure which contains references to other computer files, and possibly other directories. On many computers, directories are known as folders, or drawers to provide some relevancy to a workbench or the traditional office file cabinet. ",
            "keyString": "307384s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Sleep is a good mode to use because",
            "optionA": "  It saves power which in true is saving money ",
            "optionB": "  It makes computer fresh after it wakes up ",
            "optionC": "  It consumes low battery when you start it again ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tSleep is a good mode to use because it saves power which in true is saving money ",
            "keyString": "307826s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What hole will allocates in \"Worst-Fit\" algorithm of memory management?",
            "optionA": "  It allocates the smaller hole than required memory hole ",
            "optionB": "  It allocates the smallest hole from the available memory holes ",
            "optionC": "  It allocates the largest hole from the available memory holes ",
            "optionD": "  It allocates the exact same size memory hole ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tWorst Fit allocates a process to the partition which is largest sufficient among the freely available partitions available in the main memory. If a large process comes at a later stage, then memory will not have space to accommodate it. ",
            "keyString": "308254s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "In which addressing mode, the address of the location of the operand is given explicitly as a part of the instruction.",
            "optionA": "  absolute mode ",
            "optionB": "  immediate mode ",
            "optionC": "  index mode ",
            "optionD": "  modulus mode E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "387255s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Under virtual storage,",
            "optionA": "  a single program is processed by two or more CPUs ",
            "optionB": "  two or more programs are stored concurrently in primary storage ",
            "optionC": "  only the active pages of a program are stored in primary storage ",
            "optionD": "  interprogram interference may occur E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tUnder virtual storage only the active pages of a program are stored in primary storage. ",
            "keyString": "387771s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A base register table",
            "optionA": "  allows the programmer to write base registers and displacements explicitly in the source program. ",
            "optionB": "  is used to remember which of the general-purpose registers are currently available as base registers, and what base addresses they contain. ",
            "optionC": "  allows multiple programs to reside in separate areas of core at the same time. ",
            "optionD": "  is a term that refers to the control programs of an operating system. E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA base register table is used to remember which of the general-purpose registers are currently available as base registers, and what base addresses they contain. ",
            "keyString": "388482s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "File record length",
            "optionA": "  should always be fixed ",
            "optionB": "  Should always be variable ",
            "optionC": "  depends upon the size of the file ",
            "optionD": "  should be chosen to match the data characteristics E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tFile record length should be chosen to match the data characteristics. ",
            "keyString": "388959s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A relationship between processes such that each has some part (critical section) which must not be executed while the critical section of another is being executed, is known as",
            "optionA": "  semaphore ",
            "optionB": "  mutual exclusion ",
            "optionC": "  multiprogramming ",
            "optionD": "  multitasking E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA relationship between processes such that each has some part (critical section) which must not be executed while the critical section of another is being executed, is known as mutual exclusion ",
            "keyString": "389460s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "First operating system was developed in",
            "optionA": "  1958 ",
            "optionB": "  1976 ",
            "optionC": "  1956 ",
            "optionD": "  1946 ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe first operating system used for real work was GM-NAA I/O, produced in 1956 by General Motors' Research division for its IBM 704. ",
            "keyString": "468348s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The maximum length of any single path from the root directory?",
            "optionA": "  54 ",
            "optionB": "  63 ",
            "optionC": "  80 ",
            "optionD": "  27 ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe maximum length of any single path from the root directory is 63. ",
            "keyString": "468874s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The part of machine level instruction, which tells the central processor what has to be done, is",
            "optionA": "  Operation code ",
            "optionB": "  Address ",
            "optionC": "  Locator ",
            "optionD": "  Flip-Flop E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe part of machine level instruction, which tells the central processor what has to be done, is Operation code ",
            "keyString": "469349s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following refers to the associative memory?",
            "optionA": "  the address of the data is generated by the CPU ",
            "optionB": "  the address of the data is supplied by the users ",
            "optionC": "  there is no need for an address i.e. the data is used as an address ",
            "optionD": "  the data are accessed sequentially E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "469824s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "To avoid the race condition, the number of processes that may be simultaneously inside their critical section is",
            "optionA": "  8 ",
            "optionB": "  1 ",
            "optionC": "  16 ",
            "optionD": "  0 E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tTo avoid the race condition, the number of processes that may be simultaneously inside their critical section is 1. ",
            "keyString": "470270s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is text browser?",
            "optionA": "  Lynx ",
            "optionB": "  Hot Java ",
            "optionC": "  c. Netscape ",
            "optionD": "  Internet Explorer ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tLynx is a customizable text-based web browser for use on cursor-addressable character cell terminals. As of May 2017, it is the oldest web browser still in general use and active development, having started in 1992. ",
            "keyString": "533373s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is default location of saving and opening file?",
            "optionA": "  Desktop ",
            "optionB": "  My computer ",
            "optionC": "  My documents ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tMy documents is the default location of saving and opening the files in windows operating system. ",
            "keyString": "533651s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "By default we can save the file in",
            "optionA": "  Desktop ",
            "optionB": "  Recycle bin ",
            "optionC": "  My document ",
            "optionD": "  My computer ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "533916s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "____ is the operating systems File and folder Manager",
            "optionA": "  Windows Explorer ",
            "optionB": "  Windows Control Panel ",
            "optionC": "  My Computer ",
            "optionD": "  My Documents ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tFile Explorer, previously known as Windows Explorer, is a file manager application that is included with releases of the Microsoft Windows operating system from Windows 95 onwards. It provides a graphical user interface for accessing the file systems. ",
            "keyString": "534276s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "It is used to explorer the contents of computer, drives as well as manage files",
            "optionA": "  Recent Places ",
            "optionB": "  My Document ",
            "optionC": "  My Computer ",
            "optionD": "  My Network Place ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tMy Documents is the commonly recognized name of a special folder in Microsoft Windows This folder is supposed to be a personal area where users store their personal non-shared documents. ",
            "keyString": "534506s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following memory unit that processor can access more rapidly",
            "optionA": "  Main Memory ",
            "optionB": "  Virtual Memory ",
            "optionC": "  Cache memory ",
            "optionD": "  Read Only Memory ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tCache memory unit that processor can access more rapidly. ",
            "keyString": "617713s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Small pictures appear on the desktop",
            "optionA": "  Windows ",
            "optionB": "  Icon ",
            "optionC": "  Button ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tSmall pictures appear on the desktop is called icon ",
            "keyString": "621035s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A graphical user interface displays",
            "optionA": "  Graphics ",
            "optionB": "  Text ",
            "optionC": "  Both of Above ",
            "optionD": "  None of Above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA graphical user interface displays both Graphics and Text. ",
            "keyString": "624015s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "To change the screen saver you can go from",
            "optionA": "  Control panel display ",
            "optionB": "  Right click in desktop and properties ",
            "optionC": "  Both of Above ",
            "optionD": "  None of These ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "624562s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "You can add or remove program",
            "optionA": "  Add / Remove program from control panel ",
            "optionB": "  Delete the shortcut icon from desktop ",
            "optionC": "  Both A and B ",
            "optionD": "  None of Above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "625088s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A co-processor",
            "optionA": "  Is relatively easy to support in software ",
            "optionB": "  Causes all processor to function equally ",
            "optionC": "  Works with any application ",
            "optionD": "  Is quite common in modern computer ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA coprocessor is a computer processor used to supplement the functions of the primary processor (the CPU). Operations performed by the coprocessor may be floating point arithmetic, graphics, signal processing, string processing, cryptography or I/O Interfacing with peripheral devices. ",
            "keyString": "702376s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A Microsoft Windows is  a(n)",
            "optionA": "  Operating system ",
            "optionB": "  Graphic program ",
            "optionC": "   Word Processing ",
            "optionD": "  Database program ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tMicrosoft Windows is a group of Operating Systems manufactured by Microsoft. Windows is available in 32 and 64-bit versions and offers a graphical user interface (GUI), multitasking functionalities, virtual memory management capabilities, and support for several peripheral devices. Windows Operating Systems constitute client as well as server versions. ",
            "keyString": "702822s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is program group?",
            "optionA": "  Accessories ",
            "optionB": "  Paint ",
            "optionC": "  Word ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "703250s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which is not application software?",
            "optionA": "  Windows NT ",
            "optionB": "  Page Maker ",
            "optionC": "  WinWord XP ",
            "optionD": "  Photoshop ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tWindows NT is a family of operating systems produced by Microsoft. ",
            "keyString": "703669s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The ...... program compresses large files into a smaller file",
            "optionA": "  WinZip ",
            "optionB": "  WinShrink ",
            "optionC": "  WinStyle ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tWinZip is a Windows program that lets you archive and compress files so that you can store or distribute them more efficiently. ",
            "keyString": "704097s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Trojan-Horse programs",
            "optionA": "  are legitimate programs that allow unauthorized access ",
            "optionB": "  do not usually work ",
            "optionC": "  are hidden programs that do not show up on the system ",
            "optionD": "  usually are immediately discovered E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tTrojan-Horse programs are legitimate programs that allow unauthorized access ",
            "keyString": "800660s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "When did IBM release the first version of disk operating system DOS version 1.0?",
            "optionA": "  1981 ",
            "optionB": "  1982 ",
            "optionC": "  1983 ",
            "optionD": "  1984 E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn 1981 IBM release the first version of disk operating system DOS version 1.0. ",
            "keyString": "800720s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is false about disk when compared to main memory?",
            "optionA": "  non-volatile ",
            "optionB": "  longer storage capacity ",
            "optionC": "  lower price per bit ",
            "optionD": "  faster E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "801744s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Producer consumer problem can be solved using",
            "optionA": "  semaphores ",
            "optionB": "  event counters ",
            "optionC": "  monitors ",
            "optionD": "  all of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "801811s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Most of the microcomputer's operating systems like Apple DOS, MS DOS and PC DOS etc. are called disk operating systems because",
            "optionA": "  they are memory resident ",
            "optionB": "  they are initially stored on disk ",
            "optionC": "  they are available on magnetic tapes ",
            "optionD": "  they are partly in primary memory and partly on disk E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tMicrocomputer's operating systems like Apple DOS, MS DOS and PC DOS etc. are called disk operating systems because they are initially stored on disk ",
            "keyString": "802304s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The Primary job of the operating system is",
            "optionA": "  Manage Commands ",
            "optionB": "  Manage Users ",
            "optionC": "  Manage Programs ",
            "optionD": "  Manage Resources ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "863272s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is not an operating system?",
            "optionA": "  Windows 2000 ",
            "optionB": "  Linux ",
            "optionC": "  Mac OS ",
            "optionD": "  Notepad ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tNotepad is a simple text editor for Microsoft Windows and a basic text-editing program which enables computer users to create documents. It was first released as a mouse-based MS-DOS program in 1983, and has been included in all versions of Microsoft Windows since Windows 1.0 in 1985. ",
            "keyString": "863342s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Scandisk analyze and repair damage to which of the following?",
            "optionA": "  Physical clusters ",
            "optionB": "  FAT ",
            "optionC": "  Lost clusters ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "863720s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Find can be used to",
            "optionA": "  Locate a program ",
            "optionB": "  Locate a document ",
            "optionC": "  Locate a network computer ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "863739s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "...... is a new windows feature that offers a number of methods for searching for a file or folder?",
            "optionA": "  Find ",
            "optionB": "  Search ",
            "optionC": "  Locate ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "864101s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is true about pseudocode",
            "optionA": "  A machine language ",
            "optionB": "  An assembly language ",
            "optionC": "  A high-level language ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option E",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "938164s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The principles of structured programming forbid the use of",
            "optionA": "  WHILE-DO ",
            "optionB": "  GOTO ",
            "optionC": "  IF-THEN-ELSE ",
            "optionD": "  DO-WHILE E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "938301s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following capabilities is required for a system program to execute more than one program at a time?",
            "optionA": "  word processing ",
            "optionB": "  compiling ",
            "optionC": "  virtual memory ",
            "optionD": "  multitasking E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn computing, multitasking is the concurrent execution of multiple tasks (also known as processes) over a certain period of time. New tasks can interrupt already started ones before they finish, instead of waiting for them to end. As a result, a computer executes segments of multiple tasks in an interleaved manner, while the tasks share common processing resources such as central processing units (CPUs) and main memory. ",
            "keyString": "938347s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "For Windows 10, Microsoft released _________ in place of MS Paint.",
            "optionA": "  Paint 10 ",
            "optionB": "  New MS Paint ",
            "optionC": "  Paint 3D ",
            "optionD": "  Universal Paint ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn the April 2017 \"Creators Update\" for Windows 10, Microsoft released Paint 3D, a revamp of Paint built on Universal Windows Platform. ",
            "keyString": "938391s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the key is used to close the active window?",
            "optionA": "  Ctrl+F4 ",
            "optionB": "  Alt+F4 ",
            "optionC": "  Alt+F6 ",
            "optionD": "  Ctrl+F5 ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAlt+F4 closes the current window. ",
            "keyString": "938431s8m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "...... is used in operating system to separate mechanism from policy",
            "optionA": "  Single level implementation ",
            "optionB": "  Two level implementation ",
            "optionC": "  Multi level implementation ",
            "optionD": "  None ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "14268s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The modern keyboard typically has __________ Function keys.",
            "optionA": "  10 ",
            "optionB": "  12 ",
            "optionC": "  14 ",
            "optionD": "  16 ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe modern keyboard typically has 12 Function keys. F1, F2, F3, F4, F5, F6, F7, F8, F9, F10, F11, F12 ",
            "keyString": "15232s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Essential files of MS DOS are",
            "optionA": "  Command.com ",
            "optionB": "  Io.sys ",
            "optionC": "  Msdos.sys ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "15713s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which Operating System doesn't support long file names?",
            "optionA": "  OS / 2 ",
            "optionB": "  Windows 95 ",
            "optionC": "  MS-DOS ",
            "optionD": "  Windows NT ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tMS-DOS Operating System doesn't support long file names ",
            "keyString": "16157s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "We need system files to run",
            "optionA": "  MS Word ",
            "optionB": "  MS Excel ",
            "optionC": "  MS Dos ",
            "optionD": "  MS Access ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "16625s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which, of the following, is true for testing and debugging?",
            "optionA": "  Testing checks for logical errors in the programs, while debugging is a process of correcting those errors in the program ",
            "optionB": "  Testing detects the syntax errors in the program while debugging corrects those errors in the program ",
            "optionC": "  Testing and debugging indicate the same thing ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "70705s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Information in a memory that is no longer valid or wanted is known as",
            "optionA": "  non-volatile ",
            "optionB": "  volatile ",
            "optionC": "  surplus ",
            "optionD": "  garbage E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tInformation in a memory that is no longer valid or wanted is known as garbage. ",
            "keyString": "70840s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following filename extension suggests that the file is a backup copy of another file?",
            "optionA": "  .txt ",
            "optionB": "  .com ",
            "optionC": "  .bas ",
            "optionD": "  .bak E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn computing, \".bak\" is a filename extension commonly used to signify a backup copy of a file. When a program is about to overwrite an existing file (for example, when the user saves the document they are working on), the program may first make a copy of the existing file, with .bak appended to the filename. This common .bak naming scheme makes it possible to retrieve the original contents of the file. In a similar manner, a user may also manually make a copy of the file before the change and append .bak to the filename. ",
            "keyString": "70902s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Relocation bits used by relocating loader are specified (generated) by",
            "optionA": "  Relocating loader itself ",
            "optionB": "  Linker ",
            "optionC": "  Assembler or translator ",
            "optionD": "  Macro processor E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tRelocation bits used by relocating loader are specified (generated) by linker ",
            "keyString": "70952s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following statements is false?",
            "optionA": "  a process scheduling algorithm is preemptive if the CPU can be forcibly removed from a process ",
            "optionB": "  time sharing systems generally use preemptive CPU scheduling ",
            "optionC": "  response time are more predictable in preemptive systems than in non preemptive systems ",
            "optionD": "  real time systems generally use non-preemptive CPU scheduling E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "71000s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "If there are multiple recycle bin for a hard disk",
            "optionA": "  You can set different size for each recycle bin ",
            "optionB": "  You can choose which recycle bin to use to store your deleted files ",
            "optionC": "  You can make any one of them default recycle bin ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "118154s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Identify false statement",
            "optionA": "  You can find deleted files in recycle bin ",
            "optionB": "  You can restore any files in recycle bin if you ever need ",
            "optionC": "  You can increase free space of disk by sending files in recycle bin ",
            "optionD": "  You can right click and choose Empty Recycle Bin to clean it at once ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "118197s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "If the displayed system time and date is wrong, you can reset it using",
            "optionA": "  Write ",
            "optionB": "  Calendar ",
            "optionC": "  Write file ",
            "optionD": "  Control panel ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "118216s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "You should save your computer from?",
            "optionA": "  Viruses ",
            "optionB": "  Time bombs ",
            "optionC": "  Worms ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "118233s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "World Wide Web is being standard by",
            "optionA": "  Worldwide corporation ",
            "optionB": "  W3C ",
            "optionC": "  World Wide Consortium ",
            "optionD": "  World Wide Web Standard ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe World Wide Web Consortium is the main international standards organization for the World Wide Web. ",
            "keyString": "118249s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "You can switch from one program to another on the desktop by clicking within the desired program's window or by clicking on its ...... button",
            "optionA": "  Icon ",
            "optionB": "  Taskbar button ",
            "optionC": "  Folder ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tYou can switch from one program to another on the desktop by clicking within the desired program's window or by clicking on its \"Taskbar button\" button. ",
            "keyString": "187920s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "You can switch from one program to another by clicking within the desired program's icon from the",
            "optionA": "  Application icon on desktop ",
            "optionB": "  Application icon from taskbar ",
            "optionC": "  Folder ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tYou can switch from one program to another by clicking within the desired program's icon from the Application icon from taskbar. ",
            "keyString": "188592s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Virtual memory typically located on",
            "optionA": "  RAM ",
            "optionB": "  CPU ",
            "optionC": "  Flash card ",
            "optionD": "  Hard drive ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tVirtual memory typically located on Hard drive ",
            "keyString": "188926s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What is contained in the page table?",
            "optionA": "  Base address of each frame and corresponding page number ",
            "optionB": "  Memory address and corresponding page number ",
            "optionC": "  File name and corresponding page number ",
            "optionD": "  None of Above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tBase address of each frame and corresponding page number are contained in the page table. ",
            "keyString": "189224s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Tree structure displays the",
            "optionA": "  File only ",
            "optionB": "  Directory only ",
            "optionC": "  File and directory name ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tTree structure displays the Directory only.",
            "keyString": "189509s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following command is used to switch between the window programs?",
            "optionA": "  Alt+Tab ",
            "optionB": "  Alt+F4 ",
            "optionC": "  Ctrl+Tab ",
            "optionD": "  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAlt+Tab command is used to switch between the window programs ",
            "keyString": "245155s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "To prevent the addition and deletion of files on a disk or tape we use",
            "optionA": "  Format ",
            "optionB": "  Write protect ",
            "optionC": "  Create back up ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tWrite protection is the term used to denote the locking mechanism which prevents modification or deletion of data on a storage device. Write protection helps in the preventing accidental and intentional data modification and also helps protect against virus attacks. ",
            "keyString": "245445s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "During the boot process, the ..... looks for the system file",
            "optionA": "  CD ",
            "optionB": "  BIOS ",
            "optionC": "  CPU ",
            "optionD": "  DVD ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tDuring the boot process, the 'BIOS' looks for the system file ",
            "keyString": "245571s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following resources must be protected by the operating system?",
            "optionA": "  I/O ",
            "optionB": "  Memory ",
            "optionC": "  CPU ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "245596s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What are the two types of Semaphore?",
            "optionA": "  Digital Semaphores and Binary Semaphores ",
            "optionB": "  Analog Semaphores and Octal Semaphores ",
            "optionC": "  Counting Semaphores and Binary Semaphores ",
            "optionD": "  Critical Semaphores and System Semaphores ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tSemaphore is a simply a variable. This variable is used to solve critical section problem and to achieve process synchronization in the multi processing environment. The two most common kinds of semaphores are counting semaphores and binary semaphores. Counting semaphore can take non-negative integer values and Binary semaphore can take the value 0 & 1. only. ",
            "keyString": "245613s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The operating feature that integrates the file created in different application into WebPages",
            "optionA": "  Web integration ",
            "optionB": "  Internet integration ",
            "optionC": "  Intranet integration ",
            "optionD": "  Hypertext integration ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "299529s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which icon would you access in the printer window to install a printer drive?",
            "optionA": "  Add printer wizard ",
            "optionB": "  Setup ",
            "optionC": "  Install ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "300126s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is the allocation method of a disk space?",
            "optionA": "  Contiguous allocation ",
            "optionB": "  Linked allocation ",
            "optionC": "  Indexed allocation ",
            "optionD": "  All of the Above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "301203s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "You can set the width taskbar area and different components in it",
            "optionA": "  By right click and set width menu ",
            "optionB": "  If the taskbar is not yet locked ",
            "optionC": "  If the applications are not opened ",
            "optionD": "  If other toolbars are not enabled ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "302919s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "When you cut or copy the text or picture, it stores temporarily in the",
            "optionA": "  File ",
            "optionB": "  Clipboard ",
            "optionC": "  Icon ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe clipboard is a data buffer used for short-term data storage and/or data transfer between documents or applications used by cut, copy and paste operations and provided by the operating system. ",
            "keyString": "304532s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Advantage(s) of using assembly language rather than machine language is (are):",
            "optionA": "  It is mnemonic and easy to read. ",
            "optionB": "  Addresses any symbolic, not absolute ",
            "optionC": "  Introduction of data to program is easier ",
            "optionD": "  all of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "369923s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is not true about the memory management?",
            "optionA": "  virtual memory is used only in multi-user systems ",
            "optionB": "  segmentation suffers from external fragmentation ",
            "optionC": "  paging   suffers   from   internal fragmentation ",
            "optionD": "  segmented memory can be paged E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "370418s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Job Control Language (JCL) statements are used to",
            "optionA": "  Read the input from the slow-speed card reader to the high-speed magnetic disk ",
            "optionB": "  Specify, to the operating system, the beginning and end of a job in a batch ",
            "optionC": "  Allocate the CPU to a job ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tJCL (job control language) is a language for describing jobs (units of work) to the MVS, OS/390, and VSE operating systems, which run on IBM's S/390 large server (mainframe) computers. These operating systems allocate their time and space resources among the total number of jobs that have been started in the computer. ",
            "keyString": "370881s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Paging",
            "optionA": "  is a method of memory allocation by which the program is subdivided into equal portions, or pages and core is subdivided into equal portions or blocks. ",
            "optionB": "  consists of those addresses that may be generated by a processor during execution of a computation. ",
            "optionC": "  is a method of allocating processor time. ",
            "optionD": "  allows multiple programs to reside in separate areas of core at the time. E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn computer operating systems, paging is a memory management scheme by which a computer stores and retrieves data from secondary storage for use in main memory. In this scheme, the operating system retrieves data from secondary storage in same-size blocks called pages. Paging is an important part of virtual memory implementations in modern operating systems, using secondary storage to let programs exceed the size of available physical memory. ",
            "keyString": "371766s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is not true about documentation?",
            "optionA": "  Documentation, of a system, should be as clear and direct as possible ",
            "optionB": "  Documentation increases the maintenance time and cost ",
            "optionC": "  Documentation gives better understanding of the problem ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "372316s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A linker",
            "optionA": "  creates a load module ",
            "optionB": "  is not necessary with variable partitions ",
            "optionC": "  must be run after the loader ",
            "optionD": "  is   not   needed   with   a   good compiler E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA linker creates a load module ",
            "keyString": "421869s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Uniform Symbols Table",
            "optionA": "  contains all constants in the program ",
            "optionB": "  a permanent table of decision rules in the form of patterns for matching with the uniform symbol table to discover syntactic structure ",
            "optionC": "  consists of a full or partial list of the token's as they appear in the program. Created by Lexical analysis and used for syntax analysis and interpretation ",
            "optionD": "  a permanent table which lists all key words and special symbols of the language in symbolic form E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tUniform Symbols Table consists of a full or partial list of the token's as they appear in the program. Created by Lexical analysis and used for syntax analysis and interpretation ",
            "keyString": "421975s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "In which of the storage placement strategies a program is placed in the smallest available hole in the main memory?",
            "optionA": "  best fit ",
            "optionB": "  first fit ",
            "optionC": "  worst fit ",
            "optionD": "  buddy E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "422017s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "In which addressing mode, the effective address of the operand is generated by adding a constant value to the contents of register?",
            "optionA": "  absolute mode ",
            "optionB": "  indirect mode ",
            "optionC": "  immediate mode ",
            "optionD": "  index mode E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "422063s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The higher versions of the operating systems are so written that programs designed for earlier versions can still be run. What is it called?",
            "optionA": "  Upgradability ",
            "optionB": "  Upward mobility ",
            "optionC": "  Universality ",
            "optionD": "  Upward compatibility E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tRefers to software that runs not only on the computer for which it was designed, but also on newer and more powerful models. For example, a program designed to run on an Intel 386 microprocessor, which also runs on a Pentium, is upward compatible. Upward compatibility is important because it means you can move to a newer, larger, and more sophisticated computer without converting your data. ",
            "keyString": "422111s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Generally quick launch toolbar is displayed on",
            "optionA": "  the left side of taskbar ",
            "optionB": "  the right side of taskbar ",
            "optionC": "  on the middle of taskbar ",
            "optionD": "  a bar out of taskbar ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "480992s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which is not a valid file system?",
            "optionA": "  FAT 16 ",
            "optionB": "  FAT 32 ",
            "optionC": "  NTFS ",
            "optionD": "  FXZ ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "481026s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which file system DOS typically use?",
            "optionA": "  FAT 16 ",
            "optionB": "   FAT 32 ",
            "optionC": "  NTFS ",
            "optionD": "  LMFS ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "481040s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which file system Windows 95 typically use?",
            "optionA": "  FAT 16 ",
            "optionB": "  FAT 32 ",
            "optionC": "  NTFS ",
            "optionD": "  LMFS ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "481052s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is not a mode in starting Windows?",
            "optionA": "  Command Prompt ",
            "optionB": "  Safe Mode ",
            "optionC": "  Normal Mode ",
            "optionD": "  Turbo Mode ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "481064s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "...... controls the way in which the computer system functions and provides a means by which users can interact with the computer",
            "optionA": "  The platform ",
            "optionB": "  The operating system ",
            "optionC": "  Application software ",
            "optionD": "  The motherboard ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe operating system controls the way in which the computer system functions and provides a means by which users can interact with the computer. ",
            "keyString": "524874s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which one of the following is not a layer of operating system?",
            "optionA": "  Kernel ",
            "optionB": "  Shell ",
            "optionC": "  Application program ",
            "optionD": "  Critical selection ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tCritical selection is not a layer of the operating system ",
            "keyString": "524908s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which is not the function of the operating system?",
            "optionA": "  Memory management ",
            "optionB": "  Disk management ",
            "optionC": "  Application management ",
            "optionD": "  Virus protection ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tVirus protection is not the function of the operating system ",
            "keyString": "524926s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The virtual memory is",
            "optionA": "  An extremely large main memory ",
            "optionB": "  An extremely large secondary memory ",
            "optionC": "  An illusion of extremely large main memory ",
            "optionD": "  A type of memory used in super computer ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe virtual memory is an illusion of extremely large main memory ",
            "keyString": "524941s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Internet Explorer is",
            "optionA": "  an Internet browser ",
            "optionB": "  provided by Windows OS ",
            "optionC": "  an access point for Word Wide Web ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tInternet Explorer is a series of graphical web browsers developed by Microsoft and included in the Microsoft Windows line of operating systems, starting in 1995. ",
            "keyString": "524956s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which is not a system tool?",
            "optionA": "  Folder ",
            "optionB": "  Backup ",
            "optionC": "  Scandisk ",
            "optionD": "  Format ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "560817s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A utility that can be used to minimize the number of fragmented files and enhance the speed",
            "optionA": "  Disk space ",
            "optionB": "  Defrag ",
            "optionC": "  Scandisk ",
            "optionD": "  Double space ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "560851s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "To change the volume label",
            "optionA": "  Vol ",
            "optionB": "  Label ",
            "optionC": "  Scandisk ",
            "optionD": "  None ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "560865s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is a disk compression tools?",
            "optionA": "  Drive space ",
            "optionB": "  Defragmenter ",
            "optionC": "  Scandisk ",
            "optionD": "  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "560877s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "To save your computer from viruses you will do",
            "optionA": "  Install antivirus software and run it ",
            "optionB": "  Make physical safe for the removal disk ",
            "optionC": "  Scan the removable disk before using it ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAntivirus software, or anti-virus software, also known as anti-malware, is a computer program used to prevent, detect, and remove malware.Antivirus software was originally developed to detect and remove computer viruses, ",
            "keyString": "560888s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A bar that inform you the available options in your computer, opened applications, background running applications and can be used to switch between applications quickly is",
            "optionA": "  Menu bar ",
            "optionB": "  Tool bar ",
            "optionC": "  Status bar ",
            "optionD": "  Task bar ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "638798s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which components appear in the initial windows start up display?",
            "optionA": "  Dialog box ",
            "optionB": "  Task bar ",
            "optionC": "  Start menu ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA taskbar is an element of a graphical user interface which has various purposes. It typically shows which programs are currently running. ",
            "keyString": "638832s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Taskbar is used for",
            "optionA": "  Navigation program ",
            "optionB": "  Switching between program ",
            "optionC": "  Start a program ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAnswer: Taskbar is used to launch an application through the start menu. It displays all the opened applications and files. It is used to set taskbar and desktop properties. ",
            "keyString": "638846s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "To install the new font in window XP",
            "optionA": "  Start -> setting -> control panel -> font ",
            "optionB": "  Start -> setting -> control panel -> font -> install new font ",
            "optionC": "  Start -> control panel -> font -> install new font ",
            "optionD": "  Start -> setting -> font ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "638859s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "When a peripheral device needs immediate attention from the operating system, it generates a(n)",
            "optionA": "  Interrupt ",
            "optionB": "  Spool ",
            "optionC": "  Stack ",
            "optionD": "  Page file ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "638871s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is a phase of a compilation process",
            "optionA": "  Lexical analysis ",
            "optionB": "  Code generation ",
            "optionC": "  Both of the above ",
            "optionD": "  Static analysis E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "677017s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which are the most important features of Microsoft Windows program?",
            "optionA": "  Windows ",
            "optionB": "  Pull-down menus ",
            "optionC": "  Icons ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "677058s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following system program forgoes the production of object code to generate absolute machine code and load it into the physical main storage location from which it will be executed immediately upon completion of the assembly?",
            "optionA": "  two pass assembler ",
            "optionB": "  load-and-go assembler ",
            "optionC": "  macroprocessor ",
            "optionD": "  compiler E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "677077s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Virtual memory is",
            "optionA": "  simple to implement ",
            "optionB": "  used in all major commercial operating systems ",
            "optionC": "  less efficient in utilization of memory ",
            "optionD": "  useful when fast I/O devices are not available E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tVirtual memory is used in all major commercial operating systems ",
            "keyString": "677093s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Object code",
            "optionA": "  is ready to execute ",
            "optionB": "  is the output of compilers, but not assemblers ",
            "optionC": "  must be \"loaded\" before execution ",
            "optionD": "  must be rewritten before execution E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tObject code must be \"loaded\" before execution ",
            "keyString": "677109s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which operating system does not support long file names?",
            "optionA": "  OS/2 ",
            "optionB": "  Windows 98 ",
            "optionC": "  DOS 6.2 ",
            "optionD": "  Windows NT ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tDOS 6.2 operating system does not support long file names ",
            "keyString": "717314s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which operating system uses short file names?",
            "optionA": "  Windows ",
            "optionB": "  Unix ",
            "optionC": "  DOS ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tDOS operating system uses short file names ",
            "keyString": "717347s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Bringing a page into memory only when it is needed, this mechanism is called",
            "optionA": "  Deadlock ",
            "optionB": "  Page Fault ",
            "optionC": "  Dormant Paging ",
            "optionD": "  Demand Paging ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn computer operating systems, demand paging (as opposed to anticipatory paging) is a method of virtual memory management. In a system that uses demand paging, the operating system copies a disk page into physical memory only if an attempt is made to access it and that page is not already in memory ",
            "keyString": "717361s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "It is the default folder for many Windows Applications to save your file",
            "optionA": "  My Document ",
            "optionB": "  My Pictures ",
            "optionC": "  Documents and Settings ",
            "optionD": "  My Computer ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tMy Document is the default folder for many Windows Applications to save your file. ",
            "keyString": "717373s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The component of Windows that lets you to transfer contents from one document to another",
            "optionA": "  Briefcase ",
            "optionB": "  Clipboard ",
            "optionC": "  Document ",
            "optionD": "  Boot ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "717386s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "An instruction in a programming language that is replaced by a sequence of instructions prior to assembly or compiling is known as",
            "optionA": "  procedure name ",
            "optionB": "  macro ",
            "optionC": "  label ",
            "optionD": "  literal E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAn instruction in a programming language that is replaced by a sequence of instructions prior to assembly or compiling is known as macro. ",
            "keyString": "756638s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A program",
            "optionA": "  is a device that performs a sequence of operations specified by instructions in memory. ",
            "optionB": "  is the device where information is stored ",
            "optionC": "  is a sequence of instructions ",
            "optionD": "  is typically characterized by interactive processing and time of the CPU E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA program is a sequence of instructions ",
            "keyString": "756672s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A self-relocating program is one which",
            "optionA": "  cannot be made to execute in any area of storage other than the one designated for it at the time of its coding or translation. ",
            "optionB": "  consists of a program and relevant information for its relocation. ",
            "optionC": "  can itself performs the relocation of its address-sensitive portions. ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "756687s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Banker's algorithm for resource allocation deals with",
            "optionA": "  deadlock prevention ",
            "optionB": "  deadlock avoidance ",
            "optionC": "  deadlock recovery ",
            "optionD": "  mutual exclusion E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe Banker algorithm, sometimes referred to as the detection algorithm, is a resource allocation and deadlock avoidance algorithm developed by Edsger Dijkstra that tests for safety by simulating the allocation of predetermined maximum possible amounts of all resources, and then makes an \"s-state\" check to test for possible deadlock conditions for all other pending activities, before deciding whether allocation should be allowed to continue. ",
            "keyString": "756701s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A sequence of instructions, in a computer language, to get the desired result, is known as",
            "optionA": "  Algorithm ",
            "optionB": "  Decision Table ",
            "optionC": "  Program ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA sequence of instructions, in a computer language, to get the desired result, is known as program ",
            "keyString": "756714s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "System generation:",
            "optionA": "  is always quite simple ",
            "optionB": "  is always very difficult ",
            "optionC": "  varies in difficulty between systems ",
            "optionD": "  requires extensive tools to be understandable E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tSystem generation varies in difficulty between systems ",
            "keyString": "794698s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The Memory Address Register",
            "optionA": "  is a hardware memory device which denotes the location of the current instruction being executed. ",
            "optionB": "  is a group of electrical circuits (hardware), that performs the intent of instructions fetched from memory. ",
            "optionC": "  contains the address of the memory location that is to be read from or stored into. ",
            "optionD": "  contains a copy of the designated memory location specified by the MAR after a \"read\" or the new contents of the memory prior to a \"write\". E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe Memory Address Register contains the address of the memory location that is to be read from or stored into. ",
            "keyString": "794737s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "In virtual memory systems, Dynamic address translation",
            "optionA": "  is  the hardware necessary to implement paging ",
            "optionB": "  stores pages at a specific location on disk ",
            "optionC": "  is useless when swapping is used ",
            "optionD": "  is part of the operating system paging algorithm E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn virtual memory systems, Dynamic address translation isthe hardware necessary to implement paging ",
            "keyString": "794755s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Fragmentation of the file system",
            "optionA": "  occurs only if the file system is used improperly ",
            "optionB": "  can always be prevented ",
            "optionC": "  can be temporarily removed by compaction ",
            "optionD": "  is a characteristic of all file systems E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tFragmentation of the file system can be temporarily removed by compaction ",
            "keyString": "794771s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A non-relocatable program is one which",
            "optionA": "  can not be made to execute in any area of storage other than the one designated for it at the time of its coding or translation. ",
            "optionB": "  consists of a program and relevant information for its relocation. ",
            "optionC": "  can itself performs the relocation of its address-sensitive portions. ",
            "optionD": "  all of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA non-relocatable program is one which can not be made to execute in any area of storage other than the one designated for it at the time of its coding or translation. ",
            "keyString": "794787s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Windows 2000 server uses the",
            "optionA": "  FAT 16 ",
            "optionB": "  NTFS ",
            "optionC": "  FAT 64 ",
            "optionD": "  FAT 32 ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tWindows 2000 server uses the NTFS (New Technology File System). ",
            "keyString": "832268s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "First-in-First-Out (FIFO) scheduling is",
            "optionA": "  Non Preemptive Scheduling ",
            "optionB": "  Preemptive Scheduling ",
            "optionC": "  Fair Share Scheduling ",
            "optionD": "  Deadline Scheduling ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tFirst-in-First-Out (FIFO) scheduling is \"Non Preemptive Scheduling\". ",
            "keyString": "832482s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which one of the following key is used to refresh the active window?",
            "optionA": "  F7 ",
            "optionB": "  F8 ",
            "optionC": "  F9 ",
            "optionD": "  F5 ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\t\"F5\" key is used to refresh the active window. ",
            "keyString": "832665s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "To display system boot menu which of the following key you must press?",
            "optionA": "  F4 ",
            "optionB": "  F7 ",
            "optionC": "  F8 ",
            "optionD": "  F5 ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tTo display system boot menu F8 key you must press? ",
            "keyString": "832837s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Press ____ key while booting to display Advanced Boot Menu",
            "optionA": "  F5 ",
            "optionB": "  F6 ",
            "optionC": "  F8 ",
            "optionD": "  Del ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tPress F8 key while booting to display Advanced Boot Menu. ",
            "keyString": "832998s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The necessary conditions needed before deadlock can occur?",
            "optionA": "  No Mutual Exclusion, Hold and wait, Preemption, Circular Wait ",
            "optionB": "  Mutual Exclusion, No Hold and wait, Preemption, Circular Wait ",
            "optionC": "  Mutual Exclusion, Hold and wait, No Preemption, Circular Wait ",
            "optionD": "  Mutual Exclusion, Hold and wait, Preemption, No Circular Wait ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "871343s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The OS used to operate the mobile phone is a",
            "optionA": "  Smart card OS ",
            "optionB": "  Embedded OS ",
            "optionC": "  Multiuser OS ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "871384s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "UNIX operating system is a(n)",
            "optionA": "  Time sharing operating system ",
            "optionB": "  Multi-user operating system ",
            "optionC": "  Multi-tasking operating system ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "871404s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The ability of an operating system to control the activities of multiple program at the same time is called",
            "optionA": "  Multitasking ",
            "optionB": "  Multiprocessing ",
            "optionC": "  Multioperating ",
            "optionD": "  Multipaging ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn computing, multitasking is the concurrent execution of multiple tasks over a certain period of time. New tasks can interrupt already started ones before they finish, instead of waiting for them to end. ",
            "keyString": "871420s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Disk label name can be up to ...... characters",
            "optionA": "  8 ",
            "optionB": "  9 ",
            "optionC": "  11 ",
            "optionD": "  255 ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tDisk label name can be up to 11 characters ",
            "keyString": "871435s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Multi programming systems ......",
            "optionA": "  Are easier to develop than single programming system ",
            "optionB": "  Execute each job faster ",
            "optionC": "  Execute more jobs in the same time period ",
            "optionD": "  Are used only by large mainframe computer ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tMulti programming systems execute more jobs in the same time period ",
            "keyString": "911930s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Netscape navigator is a",
            "optionA": "  Browser ",
            "optionB": "  Compose ",
            "optionC": "  Editor ",
            "optionD": "  None of these ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tNetscape navigator is a Browser. The Netscape web browser is the general name for a series of web browsers formerly produced by Netscape Communications Corporation, a former subsidiary of AOL. ",
            "keyString": "911964s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "To print documents from Windows",
            "optionA": "  File >> Print ",
            "optionB": "  Drag the document icon over your printers icon ",
            "optionC": "  Edit print ",
            "optionD": "  Both A and B ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "911978s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following appear in Windows menu bar?",
            "optionA": "  Help ",
            "optionB": "  File ",
            "optionC": "  Edit ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "911991s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The operating system allows the user to organize the computer's contents in a hierarchical structure of directories that include all of the following except:",
            "optionA": "  Files ",
            "optionB": "  Folders ",
            "optionC": "  Drives ",
            "optionD": "  System ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "912002s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Underlined character on the menu or dialog box known as",
            "optionA": "  Hot spot ",
            "optionB": "  Hot key ",
            "optionC": "  Pane ",
            "optionD": "  Underline word ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "948737s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which key deletes text before, or to the left, of the insertion point?",
            "optionA": "  PageUp ",
            "optionB": "  Delete ",
            "optionC": "  PageDown ",
            "optionD": "  BackSpace ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "948771s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The chunks of a memory are known as",
            "optionA": "  Sector ",
            "optionB": "  Offset ",
            "optionC": "  Page ",
            "optionD": "  Frame ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "948786s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Start / restart the computer is called",
            "optionA": "  Exit ",
            "optionB": "  Run ",
            "optionC": "  Option ",
            "optionD": "  Boot ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "948798s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which file is transferred when computer is start up?",
            "optionA": "  Document ",
            "optionB": "  Program files ",
            "optionC": "  Operating system ",
            "optionD": "  System files ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "948810s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Recently deleted files are stored in",
            "optionA": "  Recycle bin ",
            "optionB": "  Desktop ",
            "optionC": "  Taskbar ",
            "optionD": "  My computer ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn computing, the Trash (also known as the Recycle Bin in Windows and by other names in other operating systems ) is temporary storage for files that have been deleted in a file manager by the user, but not yet permanently erased from the file system. Typically, a recycle bin is presented as a special file directory to the user (whether or not it is actually a single directory depends on the implementation), allowing the user to browse deleted files, undelete those that were deleted by mistake, or delete them permanently (either one by one, or by the \"Empty Trash\" function). Source : wikipedia.org ",
            "keyString": "987004s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which components appear in the initial Windows start up display?",
            "optionA": "  Dialog boxes ",
            "optionB": "  Start menu ",
            "optionC": "  Taskbar ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "987041s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A small part of taskbar that has icons of background running applications is",
            "optionA": "  Start button ",
            "optionB": "  Quick launch ",
            "optionC": "  Task bar ",
            "optionD": "  System tray ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "987060s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "An operating system version designed for use with a media center PC is Microsoft Windows XP",
            "optionA": "  Home edition ",
            "optionB": "  Media center edition ",
            "optionC": "  Tablet PC edition ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "987077s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "An operating system version designed for use with a tablet PC is Microsoft Windows XP",
            "optionA": "  Home edition ",
            "optionB": "  Media center edition ",
            "optionC": "  Tablet PC edition ",
            "optionD": "  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "987093s9m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Poor response times are caused by",
            "optionA": "  Processor busy ",
            "optionB": "  High I/O rate ",
            "optionC": "  High paging rates ",
            "optionD": "  Any of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "23964s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Link encryption",
            "optionA": "  is more secure than end-to-end encryption ",
            "optionB": "  is less secure than end-to-end encryption ",
            "optionC": "  can not be used in a public network ",
            "optionD": "  is used only to debug E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tLink encryption is less secure than end-to-end encryption. Link encryption is an approach to communications security that encrypts and decrypts all traffic at each network routing point (e.g. network switch, or node through which it passes) until arrival at its final destination. ",
            "keyString": "23997s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A form of code that uses more than one process and processor, possibly of different type, and that may on occasions have more than one process or processor active at the same time, is known as",
            "optionA": "  multiprogramming ",
            "optionB": "  multithreading ",
            "optionC": "  broadcasting ",
            "optionD": "  time sharing E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA form of code that uses more than one process and processor, possibly of different type, and that may on occasions have more than one process or processor active at the same time, is known as multithreading ",
            "keyString": "24012s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The table created by lexical analysis to describe all literals used in the source program is",
            "optionA": "  Terminal table ",
            "optionB": "  Literal table ",
            "optionC": "  Identifier table ",
            "optionD": "  Reductions E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe table created by lexical analysis to describe all literals used in the source program is Literal table. ",
            "keyString": "24025s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The term 'polling' in a computer means a process by which a computer system",
            "optionA": "  detects/corrects errors ",
            "optionB": "  multiplexes the inputs and updates the memory accordingly ",
            "optionC": "  decides correct alternative by analysing several ones ",
            "optionD": "  inquires to see if a terminal has any transaction to send E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "24038s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A tiny dot of light on the monitor is called\n",
            "optionA": "  Silicon chip ",
            "optionB": "  Optical illusion ",
            "optionC": "  Icon ",
            "optionD": "  Pixel ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA pixel is a single point in a graphic image. Graphics monitors display pictures by dividing the display screen into thousands (or millions) of pixels, arranged in rows and columns. The pixels are so close together that they appear connected. ",
            "keyString": "62705s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Who is called a supervisor of computer activity?",
            "optionA": "  Memory ",
            "optionB": "  Operating System ",
            "optionC": "  I / O Devices ",
            "optionD": "  Control Unit ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tOperating System is called a supervisor of computer activity. ",
            "keyString": "62738s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Operating System manages",
            "optionA": "  Memory ",
            "optionB": "  Processor ",
            "optionC": "  I / O devices ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "62751s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "To send email, we use",
            "optionA": "  MS Excel ",
            "optionB": "  Outlook Explorer ",
            "optionC": "  HTML ",
            "optionD": "  Netscape Navigator ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "62764s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following concept is best to preventing page faults?",
            "optionA": "  Paging ",
            "optionB": "  The working set ",
            "optionC": "  Hit ratios ",
            "optionD": "  Address location resolution ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "62775s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "User-Friendly Systems are:",
            "optionA": "  required    for    object-oriented programming ",
            "optionB": "  easy to develop ",
            "optionC": "  common among traditional mainframe operating systems ",
            "optionD": "  becoming more common E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tUser-Friendly Systems are becoming more common ",
            "keyString": "103328s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following addressing modes, facilitates access to an operand whose location is defined relative to the beginning of the data structure in which it appears?",
            "optionA": "  ascending ",
            "optionB": "  sorting ",
            "optionC": "  index ",
            "optionD": "  indirect E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "103362s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "While running DOS on a PC, which command would be used to duplicate the entire diskette?",
            "optionA": "  COPY ",
            "optionB": "  DISKCOPY ",
            "optionC": "  CHKDSK ",
            "optionD": "  TYPE E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "103375s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Memory",
            "optionA": "  is a device that performs a sequence of operations specified by instructions in memory. ",
            "optionB": "  is the device where information is stored ",
            "optionC": "  is a sequence of instructions ",
            "optionD": "  is   typically   characterized   by interactive processing and time-slicing of the CPU E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tMemory is the device where information is stored. ",
            "keyString": "103388s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following rules out the use of GO TO?",
            "optionA": "  Flowchart ",
            "optionB": "  HIPO-DIAGRAMS ",
            "optionC": "  Nassi-Shneiderman diagram ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "103400s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Memory management is :",
            "optionA": "  not used in modern operating system ",
            "optionB": "  replaced with virtual memory on current systems ",
            "optionC": "  not used on multiprogramming systems ",
            "optionD": "  critical  for even the simplest operating systems E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tMemory management is criticalfor even the simplest operating systems ",
            "keyString": "143549s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The initial value of the semaphore that allows only one of the many processes to enter their critical sections, is",
            "optionA": "  8 ",
            "optionB": "  1 ",
            "optionC": "  16 ",
            "optionD": "  0 E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe initial value of the semaphore that allows only one of the many processes to enter their critical sections, is 1. ",
            "keyString": "143585s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The Register - to - Register (RR) instructions",
            "optionA": "  have both their operands in the main store. ",
            "optionB": "  which perform an operation on a register operand and an operand which is located in the main store, generally leaving the result in the register, except in the case of store operation when it is also  ",
            "optionC": "  which perform indicated operations on two fast registers of the machine and leave the result in one of the registers. ",
            "optionD": "  all of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe Register - to - Register (RR) instructions which perform indicated operations on two fast registers of the machine and leave the result in one of the registers. ",
            "keyString": "143599s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A page fault",
            "optionA": "  is an error is a specific page ",
            "optionB": "  occurs when a program accesses a page of memory ",
            "optionC": "  is   an   access   to   a   page   not currently in memory ",
            "optionD": "  is a reference to a page belonging to another program E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA page fault (sometimes called #PF, PF or hard fault) is a type of exception raised by computer hardware when a running program accesses a memory page that is not currently mapped by the memory management unit (MMU) into the virtual address space of a process. ",
            "keyString": "143611s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "An algorithm is best described as",
            "optionA": "  A computer language ",
            "optionB": "  A step by step procedure for solving a problem ",
            "optionC": "  A branch of mathematics ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAn algorithm is best described as a step by step procedure for solving a problem ",
            "keyString": "143624s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the key is used to close the active window?",
            "optionA": "  Ctrl+F4 ",
            "optionB": "   Ctrl+F5 ",
            "optionC": "  Alt+F6 ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tCtrl+W & Alt+F4 is used to close the active window. ",
            "keyString": "183426s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The shortcut key to open a task manager is:",
            "optionA": "  Alt + F1 ",
            "optionB": "  Alt + Ctrl + Delete ",
            "optionC": "  Alt + Tab ",
            "optionD": "  F1 ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe shortcut key to open a task manager is \"Alt + Ctrl + Delete\". ",
            "keyString": "183460s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The windows feature is the ability of computer to automatically configure a new hardware component is that",
            "optionA": "  Auto detect ",
            "optionB": "  Plug and play ",
            "optionC": "  Add remove hardware ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn computing, a plug and play device or computer bus, is one with a specification that facilitates the discovery of a hardware component in a system without the need for physical device configuration ",
            "keyString": "183475s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is not a part of the control panel?",
            "optionA": "  Date and time ",
            "optionB": "  My documents ",
            "optionC": "  Add or remove program ",
            "optionD": "  Display ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tMy documents is not a part of the control panel. ",
            "keyString": "183487s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The ...... provides information about hardware installation, configuration and hardware status",
            "optionA": "  Device manager ",
            "optionB": "  Control panel ",
            "optionC": "  Add new hardware ",
            "optionD": "  Program manager ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe Device manager provides information about hardware installation, configuration and hardware status. ",
            "keyString": "183500s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A system program that combines the separately compiled modules of a program into a form suitable for execution",
            "optionA": "  assembler ",
            "optionB": "  linking loader ",
            "optionC": "  cross compiler ",
            "optionD": "  load and go E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA system program that combines the separately compiled modules of a program into a form suitable for execution is linking loader. ",
            "keyString": "223506s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Process is",
            "optionA": "  program in High level language kept on disk ",
            "optionB": "  contents of main memory ",
            "optionC": "  a program in execution ",
            "optionD": "  a job in secondary memory E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tProcess is a program in execution. ",
            "keyString": "223541s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Addressing structure",
            "optionA": "  defines the fundamental method of determining effective operand addresses ",
            "optionB": "  are variations in the use of fundamental addressing structures, or some associated actions which are related to addressing. ",
            "optionC": "  performs indicated operations on two fast registers of the machine and leave the result in one of the registers. ",
            "optionD": "  all of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAddressing structure is defines the fundamental method of determining effective operand addresses. ",
            "keyString": "223556s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The Memory Buffer Register (MBR)",
            "optionA": "  is a hardware memory device which denotes the location of the current instruction being executed. ",
            "optionB": "  is a group of electrical circuits (hardware), that performs the intent of instructions fetched from memory. ",
            "optionC": "  contains the address of the memory location that is to be read from or stored into. ",
            "optionD": "  contains a copy of the designated memory location specified by the MAR after a \"read\" or the new contents of the memory prior to a \"write\". E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe Memory Buffer Register (MBR) contains a copy of the designated memory location specified by the MAR after a \"read\" or the new contents of the memory prior to a \"write\". ",
            "keyString": "223569s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The strategy of allowing processes that are logically runnable to be temporarily suspended is called",
            "optionA": "  preemptive scheduling ",
            "optionB": "  non preemptive scheduling ",
            "optionC": "  shortest job first ",
            "optionD": "  first come first served E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe strategy of allowing processes that are logically runnable to be temporarily suspended is called preemptive scheduling. ",
            "keyString": "223582s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The register or main memory location which contains the effective address of the operand is known as",
            "optionA": "  pointer ",
            "optionB": "  indexed register ",
            "optionC": "  special location ",
            "optionD": "  scratch pad E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe register or main memory location which contains the effective address of the operand is known as pointer. ",
            "keyString": "267180s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Assembly code data base is associated with",
            "optionA": "  assembly language version of the program which is created by the code generation phase and is input to the assembly phase. ",
            "optionB": "  a permanent table of decision rules in the form of patterns for matching with the uniform symbol table to discover syntactic structure. ",
            "optionC": "  consists of a full or partial list or the token ",
            "optionD": "  a permanent table which lists all key words and special symbols of the language in symbolic form. E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAssembly code data base is associated with the assembly language version of the program which is created by the code generation phase and is input to the assembly phase. ",
            "keyString": "267214s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Thrashing can be avoided if",
            "optionA": "  the pages, belonging to the working set of the programs, are in main memory ",
            "optionB": "  the speed of CPU is increased ",
            "optionC": "  the speed of I/O processor is increased ",
            "optionD": "  all of the above E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThrashing can be avoided if the pages, belonging to the working set of the programs, are in main memory. ",
            "keyString": "267230s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "In analyzing the compilation of PL/I program, the term \"Lexical analysis\" is associated with",
            "optionA": "  recognition of basic syntactic constructs through reductions. ",
            "optionB": "  recognition of basic elements and creation of uniform symbols ",
            "optionC": "  creation of more optional matrix. ",
            "optionD": "  use of macro processor to produce more optimal assembly code E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn analyzing the compilation of PL/I program, the term \"Lexical analysis\" is associated with recognition of basic elements and creation of uniform symbols. ",
            "keyString": "267244s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Resolution of externally defined symbols is performed by",
            "optionA": "  Linker ",
            "optionB": "  Loader ",
            "optionC": "  Compiler ",
            "optionD": "  Assembler E.  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tResolution of externally defined symbols is performed by Linker ",
            "keyString": "267256s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Driver is",
            "optionA": "  Hardware controller ",
            "optionB": "  Hardware and gain controller ",
            "optionC": "  Data controller ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA program that controls a device. Every device, whether it be a printer, disk drive, or keyboard, must have a driver program. Many drivers, such as the keyboard driver, come with the operating system. For other devices, you may need to load a new driver when you connect the device to your computer.",
            "keyString": "308160s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "System files allocated at",
            "optionA": "  Boot area ",
            "optionB": "  FAT area ",
            "optionC": "  Data area ",
            "optionD": "  Directory ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tSystem files allocated at Boot area ",
            "keyString": "308194s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "...... transforms one interface into other interface",
            "optionA": "  Program ",
            "optionB": "  Software ",
            "optionC": "  Data ",
            "optionD": "  None ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tSoftware transforms one interface into other interface ",
            "keyString": "308208s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "........ interface consists of thing like program counter, register, interrupts and terminal",
            "optionA": "  Hardware ",
            "optionB": "  Software ",
            "optionC": "  Data ",
            "optionD": "  None ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tHardware interface consists of thing like program counter, register, interrupts and terminal ",
            "keyString": "308220s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "....... show characteristics with both hardware and software",
            "optionA": "  Operating system ",
            "optionB": "  Software ",
            "optionC": "  Data ",
            "optionD": "  None ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tOperating system show characteristics with both hardware and software ",
            "keyString": "308232s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Save operation means",
            "optionA": "  Put data into processor ",
            "optionB": "  Put data into internal memory ",
            "optionC": "  Put data into secondary storage ",
            "optionD": "  Put data into monitor ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "344689s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "CAD software is most likely to be used by",
            "optionA": "  Web designer ",
            "optionB": "  Engineers ",
            "optionC": "  Project Manager ",
            "optionD": "  Magazine Editor ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tComputer-aided design (CAD) is the use of computer systems to aid in the creation, modification, analysis, or optimization of a design. CAD software is used to increase the productivity of the designer, improve the quality of design, improve communications through documentation, and to create a database for manufacturing. ",
            "keyString": "344724s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A spooler is a",
            "optionA": "  Location in memory that maintains the contents of documents until it prints out ",
            "optionB": "  Queue of print job that are waiting to print ",
            "optionC": "  Program that coordinates the print job that are waiting to process ",
            "optionD": "  Message sent from the printer to the operating system when a print job is completed ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA program that controls spooling -- putting jobs on a queue and taking them off one at a time. Most operating systems come with one or more spoolers, such as a print spooler for spooling documents. In addition, some applications include spoolers. Many word processors, for example, include their own print spooler. A good print spooler should allow you to change the order of documents in the queue and to cancel specific print jobs. Source : webopedia.com ",
            "keyString": "344738s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The problem with .... file is that they slow your computer's operation",
            "optionA": "  Fragmented ",
            "optionB": "  Formatted ",
            "optionC": "  Program ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn computer storage, fragmentation is a phenomenon in which storage space is used inefficiently, reducing capacity or performance and often both. The exact consequences of fragmentation depend on the specific system of storage allocation in use and the particular form of fragmentation. ",
            "keyString": "344751s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "User action such as keystroke or mouse click are referred to as",
            "optionA": "  Interrupt ",
            "optionB": "  Tasks ",
            "optionC": "  Processes ",
            "optionD": "  Event ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": "\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tNo explanation is given for this questionLet's Discuss on Board ",
            "keyString": "344763s10m42h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        }
    ]
}